Thank you to just Matt for subscribing to this channel.
You have been noticed.
Welcome.
What's up everybody?
Yes Matt, it is I.
It is God.
Oh wait, I had to I had the thing off.
Shit.
Hold on.
Yes, Matt, it is I.
God Himself.
And thank you to Isanti as well.
Again.
Subscribe for three months.
Yippee!
Alright, no more of that.
No more of that.
Oh yeah.
Guys, I had a dream about Noiter.
I shit you not.
I had a dream that I was making a wand.
And I made the most insane wand ever.
Like it was so much damage and it was amazing in every aspect.
But then I changed something and I couldn't get it back to what it was.
And I had to let it go.
I had a brief moment of just pure bliss and I couldn't make the wand that I had before again.
I forgot what I did.
Oh man.
I'm starting to dream about this game.
This is getting a little too crazy.
Dreams have started.
Is that a common thing?
Hold on.
Hopefully the filter is not on anymore.
Okay, it's not good.
Was the dream an FPS or like the game camera?
I'm actually not sure Mr. Beat.
I can't remember.
I just remember the feeling of losing that wand that I had made or like the combination of spells.
You have the Tetris effect.
Actually I've heard about that.
I mean I have dreamt about games before especially World of Warcraft.
When I play certain things for long periods and I start to dream about them.
I don't think it's that uncommon.
Okay.
Today's a big day.
Well, I think I may try to just to change it up a bit.
I may try to go for a win.
See how how well I could manage that if I really wanted to.
Because in my mind I'm like oh I can easily win the game.
Like if I need a win I can easily do that.
But I'm not so sure.
With the knowledge that I have now maybe I can.
I think it's a good thing to try.
And if things go really well who knows.
Maybe I'll do something else explore other regions.
But for now I think I'll try to go for a win.
I haven't decided yet.
I'm 50-50.
I'm just gonna play.
See what spells I get.
See how it goes.
You know.
And if things align,
if the Okay.
Win a nightmare run?
Nah, I'm keep sticking to normal for now.
I'm having enough trouble as it is.
Oh, Ujiri!
Thank you for raiding.
Thank you for that.
Rust.
Zombie poop.
Wait, did I pronounce your name correctly?
How's everybody?
You should try a nightmare just once at least.
Oh, I will.
I will.
I'm just still sticking to this for now.
After last time I've discovered so many new things.
I want to do that again also.
All those spells we found in the sky?
My god, man.
I want to find them again and try them.
I have so many things to do.
Fliksoik.
Dankhe fritze mornad.
Dankeschön.
Okay, guys.
I'm too excited.
I gotta jump in.
Yup.
Switch over.
Hopefully I won't fog anything up.
So the map situation should be solved now.
The audio situation should be solved now.
You can hear the game.
Everything's good.
Let me just see the meters.
I am thinking of maybe I should put the chat up on my second screen as well just to have it.
Just in case some of those situations arise when you guys can't really tell me something's wrong.
It's actually a big problem I have.
I need to find an elegant solution for that.
Maybe I'll do that at some point.
For now though, the air is filled with fungal spores.
Oh-ho-ho.
So, I believe that is the gods telling us we need to get high.
Hold on, there's a fungus right there.
Let's eat it.
Oh, that's the bad fungus.
Uh-oh.
That does not make you high.
That makes you puke.
Yeah, you don't want to eat that.
Okay, that's good to know though.
You know what?
Just in general, I want to try and eat more things.
Also, is that?
Oh, that's snow.
But that still works.
Yeah, make it snow.
Feels good to be back in the game.
Is everything sort of muted in color?
I feel like there's a weird effect going on right here.
It may be the fungal spores or whatever.
It's gotta be.
Okay, I gotta find water.
Thank you.
Oh, you know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna find the tablet so I can get more money.
Oh, but hold on, the tablet is somewhere on the right, it seems.
How to get... Look at all that oil!
There's way too much of that.
Oh god.
Blow it.
Why
won't that?
Okay, there we go.
I don't think I was hitting it.
What's that?
Slimy egg.
You know what?
Why not?
Let's have a slimy egg.
So if it's called slimy, maybe I can do something with it with slime.
Maybe if I put it in a pool of slime, something happens.
Okay, I want to go to the right, because I want to find a tablet.
Where'd the money go?
Also, what do I have?
I have bombs.
Okay.
Bombs are okay.
Oh my, there's too much oil!
Can't go anywhere.
Eh, hold on, I can set it on fire though.
That's not a bad idea.
Yes!
And then we just leave that be for now.
Man, it is hot where I live right now.
Very uncomfortable.
It's like very humid and very hot at the same time.
Sucks.
That money.
That is, what is that?
Acceleration.
I already have it.
I should kill these guys to get the money.
Whoops!
Oh, okay.
We're probably fine.
That guy died.
This is the run, by the way, where I achieve everything that I will set out to do.
I can feel it, you know?
Also, where are all the mushrooms?
I want to get high.
We're definitely getting high this run.
Okay, that's a decent amount of money there.
Very good.
Oh, are these guys here because of the mushrooms?
I was wondering, what the hell are these guys doing here?
It makes sense.
I mean, it's a lot of money actually.
It's like finding a whole family of hamises.
That's just straight up money.
Essentially, you're a hit man in this game.
You get paid to murder all these creatures.
Ah!
Oh my goodness!
That was terrible.
Wait for them.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
There we go.
Oh my, these are endless.
Holy shit.
Okay.
Lots of money.
Can I finally get to the tablet?
Actually, maybe.
I'm gonna blow it.
Oh,
he's gonna burn alive.
Look at all that oil.
Holy crap.
Yeah, I'm not risking that.
Just ignore it.
Get some water going.
Wait, are we full on snow?
No, not really.
Okay, we're at the edge now.
This is it.
Tablet time.
The tablet is nice for some aoe damage as well.
Let's not use that here.
Actually, yes.
Wait, he didn't die from that.
Wow.
You.
Yeah.
That was sick.
Give me another slimy egg.
You know what?
No, keep the slimy egg for now.
I was gonna break it.
But the companion is gonna come out.
Getting good amount of money here.
We are paying for it though with some HP.
Shit.
You know what?
Let's go.
It is what it is.
Let me not take that just yet.
Let's see here.
Okay, perks.
Is that?
There we go.
That is a fantastic first perk to get.
Love that.
Give me that one.
Yes.
Okay, that's not good.
I think I like this.
I'll buy that one.
I'll buy this one.
What is this one again?
Homebringer teleport bolt.
I don't like that.
Maybe I like this.
I definitely like that.
Do I like torch?
I think I do like torch.
Maybe I like two rocks.
Okay, let's see what I can do.
This is digging.
Well, this is also digging.
They're both kind of digging.
But what if I do energy sphere with timer on that?
What then?
Right.
Oh, actually.
Wait a second.
I think I just learned something very basic about this game.
I think when it says timer, it's not always on a timer, but if it hits something, it's actually just more like a trigger.
I thought no matter what, that would be like, let's say I shot it here, it would never trigger because it wouldn't have time to actually time out, if that makes sense.
What the fuck?
How did I never realize?
Look, it doesn't matter when it always shoots.
That's interesting.
Not bad.
Oh, but I run out of mana quick with it.
Look at that.
That's almost instantaneous oom.
That costs 50 mana?
How about we do this instead?
It's a little better, I guess.
Or maybe it's just not worth it with that right now.
We just don't have the mana for it.
Although it is good to have the damage.
And this does how much?
Five damage and five slice.
Okay, it's more like a shotgun, I guess, but that's fine.
Let's shotgun it up.
I like it.
Let's run with this.
And Stuart, are we gonna... can we even?
No, there's no way to even make him angry.
So we just leave.
We played safe.
This is the new ruleset.
We're gonna make the next holy mountain our home base, if we can.
And murder Stuart.
Let's see this.
Oh, that's not bad.
That's a proper shotgun.
Oh, yeah!
Did the timer stick?
Sir?
There we go.
There's a guy up here.
Oh, hello.
Gotcha.
Oh, yeah.
The pollen is... oh, hello!
He has a wand.
What wand does thou process?
Oh, shit.
I'm scared.
He doesn't shoot it.
I'm scared of it.
Is that wand empty?
I'm hitting him.
Sir, wake up.
Wow, he actually fights the enemies too, it seems.
Bro, this guy has so much HP.
All right.
Oh, circle of stillness.
I think I like it.
That's a good one.
In fact, circle of stillness into tablet.
I wonder if that will deal with Stuart.
Circle of stillness into tablet.
It will give me enough time to position myself and throw the tablet.
That is an option.
I mean, we're so early on, it doesn't matter if we fail.
It's an experiment.
Give me that gold.
This is a solid digging wand.
Really solid.
Oh, what a shot.
What a shot.
Okay, let me try and eat this guy now.
Okay, I take damage from that.
I promise, I will eat everything.
Even this guy.
Okay, doesn't do anything.
But I guess it does do something.
If you have the perk where...
What is it?
Where you take damage if you're below a certain percentage of HP.
And you can actually get satiated by eating.
So that's something.
Okay, getting some good money here.
$1,100 is very respectable.
According to myself.
Are you the one shooting?
Causing a ruckus.
I think when we reach, let's say, 20 HP, we go back and heal.
Something like that.
I'm optimizing very much right now.
Let's go this way.
Oh, for some reason, that goes down.
That means there's an enemy down there.
Oh, that looks not good.
That actually looks kind of bad.
Yep.
Let's leave that be for now.
Give me some of that gold.
Let's not go too deep in case we need to go back and heal.
So I have an easy access back.
Shit, why won't that destroy?
Uh-oh.
He's not dead.
Now he is.
Come on, this is the time to give me some hearts.
Now that I have stronger hearts.
It's a golden opportunity for me to make a lot of HP happen here.
Bam.
This thing is vibing out.
Let me destroy that.
Don't shoot me.
Do not.
Oh man, I'm in such a fantastic mood today, man.
I don't know.
I just can't stop smiling today.
Something really nice happened in my life today.
And I will share that in approximately half a year.
I can't explain why, but...
Oh my god, we're dying.
Okay, that's our cue to go back.
We're leaving.
Get watered?
Back the same way we came from.
Come on.
Wait, where am I going?
This way.
Okay, there's a guy there.
Let's play it ultra safe.
Wait, that didn't come from there.
I will not bother with that guy.
Straight back.
Don't even stand on any of the toxic stuff.
Just go.
I'm ready to shoot the first guy that comes into vision.
There's a lava.
Be careful.
Wait, where the fuck did I enter?
Oh, over here, I think.
Shit.
Oh, fuck me.
No, you asshole.
Well played, sir.
Well played.
God damn it.
Fuck, I was so close.
That's what you get for squeezing the lemon and playing it like that.
I was way too low on HP, man.
That is...
Yeah.
I mean, I think I did all right.
Walking around with 40 HP.
But then out of nowhere, I just lost like 35.
That was a big blunder on my part.
It's as simple as that.
I effed up.
Yeah.
Okay.
Doink.
No!
Come on, doink me.
There we go.
Love the doink.
Can I get the tablet?
Oh, you asshole.
All right, we gotta wait a bit.
Just wait a bit here.
Okay, that should be enough.
Plop.
No!
Ah, got it.
All right, put it here.
From the get go, we can now throw the tablet and get more gold.
How... you know what?
I'm gonna make a personal challenge for myself.
Okay, watch this.
In this hemisphere, I will only kill with the tablet.
This is the challenge.
Because if I can get good at this, I think it's really good skill to have.
We're doing it.
What?!
Guys, it's a bad start.
Somehow that didn't kill him.
Okay, let me kill this guy and then we start the challenge.
The challenge has not begun yet.
Also this guy.
Okay, now the challenge starts.
Here we go.
Okay, wait a minute.
The challenge starts now.
Now we start.
That was an unlucky beginning, okay?
I'm not cheating.
I'm not.
Okay, what do I have?
I have six more of those magic missiles.
That's what they're called, right?
Magic missiles.
What is that up there?
Flammoxium!
You know what?
If I can get to that easily, I will actually grab it.
Because I also want to experiment with mixing liquids.
So we're going to be doing some of that.
I just feel like there's very few combinations that work.
I've tried a bunch of things.
Oh wait, we don't shoot.
We tablet.
Only tablet.
He's going to kill himself.
That works too.
Is that Ambrosia?
Yeah.
I should start using this more, you know?
Like before I go into battle, just a bit of the old...
Like that.
And it actually lasts like...
It's like a solid three, five seconds.
That's enough for like a little encounter.
Right?
So I do like that.
Then I go in.
That's for you, sir.
Not bad at all.
Because I've noticed that my...
Like I have all these potions up here, but I rarely use them.
And that's kind of dumb.
Shit.
All right, fine.
We're gonna fuck the challenge.
Fuck the challenge.
It's a bad idea.
I'm not skilled enough.
I freely admit it.
Man, it smells really nice.
I think my neighbor's cooking up something fierce in the kitchen.
Okay, so the best way to get in there is obviously to make a hole up here, I think.
Boink.
Ah, I hate this wand.
The mana recharge is atrocious.
Let me grab another one in the meanwhile.
The last magic missile sucked?
We got a new one.
I had it returned.
Easy.
Rain cloud.
Not bad.
I do like me some rain cloud.
Why, you may ask?
Well, that's a good question.
That's Pete.
Wait a minute.
You're feeling pressure inside.
Oh, right.
What was that thing called that I ate?
Was it Pete's soup or something?
I had like soup at some point that I could eat.
I don't think it...
No, it was like...
Not Pete.
Peas.
Peas soup.
Like the little green balls.
And I'm not talking about bouncing burst here.
Order all of that.
Can I...
Just do it.
Do it.
And this guy.
Boink, up here.
That's for you.
Oh, look, look.
Fantastic.
What a kick.
What's up?
Yo, horta.
Oh, he wants some too.
What is...
Up!
Shit.
Come here.
Yeah.
Totally worth it.
In fact, I have two tablets now.
I can dual wheel tablets.
One in each hand.
Wow, what a dodge.
This guy right here.
Oh no, and I'm gonna...
This is...
He's kicking my ass.
Uh oh.
Oh wait, I have backup tablets.
There we go.
Who needs a wand?
I don't.
Oh, he did not die, nevermind.
This asshole.
So his projectiles actually deflect my tablets, which is kind of annoying.
Dang it.
Okay, yeah, this is bad.
I need to be the bigger man here and walk away.
And come back later when he's gone.
Oh, would you look at that now?
I'm getting in.
That could be a hard in there.
That's way too fiery right now.
Nice!
How did I miss that one?
That was terrible.
I'm so disappointed with myself.
I thought I'd built up all this skill.
And yet, I didn't.
Oh no, oh no, oh no.
Get, get, give me, give me.
Hey asshole.
Oh nice, he died to the water.
Very good, very good.
Okay, it's going okay.
Could be better, but it's not the worst.
It's definitely not the worst.
I've had worse.
Anything in here?
Tablet!
The dodges!
Fuck me, there's so much toxic shit.
Can't stand anywhere.
Okay, there's a couple of hammers.
I'm out of water.
Just kidding.
Flammoxium.
Oh my god, please don't get hit by that.
This is a tough hemisphere.
I'm having a bad time here.
Come on.
There we go.
That wasn't too bad.
Give me that.
Of course, I'm poisoned.
Look at all that lava.
What a disaster.
Phew.
Shit, I'm poisoned again.
I think it's time to leave.
I'm not kidding.
This is going horribly.
16 HP.
Yeah, we're out of here.
Let's find the nearest portal that isn't surrounded by lava.
What is that?
Is that a tablet?
Oh, it is.
I forgot it.
Gimme.
And gimme.
Nope.
You know what?
I'll keep it.
I'll keep the flammoxium.
Oh, but hold on.
This portal is rip.
Look at that.
So it seems like you don't have to empty the teleportation there for the portal to disappear.
You just need to break the chamber containing it.
All right, let's go.
Heal up.
Take no chances here.
185.
That's not too bad.
The drill!
Very cool.
Okay.
Ayy, perk lottery!
I'm taking that one.
Can't go wrong with that, I don't think.
Now, what do I want my main one to be?
This has a lot of slots, doesn't it?
But it is shuffle.
That sucks.
I need something that is non-shuffle and has a lot of slots.
That would make me very happy.
Shuffle, shuffle, non-shuffle, but only two slots.
I think this one is the best bet.
But I don't have the money for it!
Fuck!
Oh, that's bad.
This one can dig, though.
So that means I can get money quick and come back.
Not too bad.
Yeah, I'm taking this.
Replace...
I guess.
Hold on.
Put these one up here.
And buy that one.
Yeah.
That seems good.
And we have these.
And we can do this stuff.
That's not bad.
0.4, 0.72.
Oh, that's a really good one right there.
Some straight-up spark-bolt action, maybe.
Or even...
Oh, that's very nice.
But the mana recharge is crap.
So, in fact, it is not very nice.
That one is way too slow in mana recharge.
That's too slow.
That sucks.
It's gotta be this one.
Pop, pop, pop.
That's not bad.
That's the digging one.
And for the damage...
Too slow.
It's not the worst.
Although it kind of is.
Let's make that a little better.
Okay, that's not bad.
That's not bad.
That's actually very good.
Then we have this guy right here for high-value targets.
Maybe I'll put it on that one.
This one is kind of suck anyway.
We could do something like that because why not?
Or leave it here so we can replace the wand.
That's even better.
And leave this one up here so I can throw this wand away in case I want to later on.
But I still kind of want this later, you know?
Very nice.
All right, let's go.
Decent start.
I can't make him mad.
So we just move.
There's a bit of a careless start there for sure.
That hemisphere could have gone better for sure.
I was at fault.
Get some money.
I really want that wand for 400.
I'm gonna save up for that one.
Where are you?
Did you die?
Shotgun man.
No, there you are.
He has a wand!
Firebolt with trigger, but only 21 of them.
Thanks.
Give me gold.
Look at that, 261 already.
I can't state how important it is to have the digging wand in this level.
Everything is like soft, you know?
And there's so much gold everywhere.
That should actually become one of my main priorities, you know?
Like, so stage one, the very first level, I'm just gonna...
So the priority there is to get some money, find some wands, and maybe some hearts.
And then move on, basically.
Just get out of there.
And then this stage right here, it's all about being able to dig.
Because if you can dig, you can get money.
And if you can get money, you can always get all the things that your heart desires.
Ow!
Oh my god!
That was bad.
To be fair, I have a shit wand.
That is my excuse.
Is anything in here?
Hold on, what's that?
No, okay.
That's where we came from.
That was a sick dodge.
Some water.
Oh, wait, wait!
No, nothing.
I actually have a lot of HP.
How do I have so much already?
210?
Did I find that many hearts in the first level?
I have no memory of that.
I must have.
Odd.
Didn't feel like a good hemisphere, but I guess it was in a way.
Like, look at this.
This whole area is now completely fucked because of one enemy.
Yikes.
It's one of my most hated enemies in the beginning of the game.
And these guys too.
Every enemy is my most hated enemy.
These guys are okay.
Okay.
I can deal with those.
Anything hiding in here?
Okay.
I want that wand.
Yo!
That is a pretty good wand as well.
Holy crap.
I mean, only two slots, that kind of sucks.
But other than that, not bad.
I'll even replace it with this one.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah.
Yeah, my beloved.
We meet again.
I will only use this for, like, big enemies, pretty much.
The fuck?
Oh, that's scary.
He's using some kind of laser.
There he is.
Oh!
Fuck you.
Gee, look at that spell.
That's terrifying.
Aiming arc.
Shuffle.
Dude, a lot of mana, though.
Thanks.
I should try to make some kind of wand out of that one.
Because if you think about it, the plasma cutter actually does insane damage to enemies.
And that is, like, a weaponized plasma cutter.
So if I can do something with that, I think it could be very, very deadly.
Wait.
122 HP, not bad.
Oh, dude, we gotta go to fungal caverns.
We gotta get high.
Fuck yeah, let's go.
Immediately.
It's all I want.
Whoops, don't fall into that.
Go west.
Whoa!
Thanks.
Not a big dude.
The lightning bolt.
One of my favorite spells.
If I can find explosive immunity and electricity immunity, that thing could shred.
I mean, it still shreds, but it's just very dangerous.
You can, like, go brainless then, you know, when you are immune.
You.
Notice how they're electrified a little while after.
I do wonder what happens if that electrified body falls into water, if it still, like, electrifies it.
Also, didn't I see a wand over here?
Something was shining just before, out of my eye.
Out of the corner of my eye.
What was that?
Oh yeah, there was something there.
Some arrows.
With sparkly bounce.
I mean...
No, it's kind of bad, right?
Although...
I mean, it's not too bad.
There come the sparkling bounces.
But I think I like mine more.
These do five damage slice.
Actually, hold on.
The arrow reduces spread by minus 20.
Look at that.
That's kind of a big deal.
That means if you put this on a wand that is, like, very inaccurate, you can make it accurate.
I never noticed.
I need to pay more attention to the actual, like, status changes that a spell will also do, other than the spell itself.
I think I will...
You know what?
I'll take this.
We need to experiment with more spells.
Fuck yeah, let's shoot some arrows.
Where we'll become Robin Hood.
Except I keep all the money for myself.
Okay, you know what?
This one sucks.
The spark bolt is way better.
Oh my goodness.
I'm taking this back.
I need to survive first and foremost.
Oh my goodness!
All right, I guess we leave.
No fungal caverns for us.
It's over.
Jesus.
This game is turning on me.
Not having good luck right now.
Or skill, for that matter.
Don't shoot me.
Lord.
There we go.
I'm leaving.
It's not going too well here.
Not gonna lie.
This is bad.
Come on.
Do something nice for me now.
Aha!
Chainsaws?
I like that.
Living on the edge?
No.
That one is really cool.
But won't that...
Wait a minute.
This is pretty much a surefire way to get to the top.
Whenever I want.
Right?
But I would rather have something else.
Now that I like.
Unlimited spells, baby.
Hell yeah.
Okay.
What do I want unlimited?
Do I have any rocks?
I need rocks.
Definitely gonna buy this one for sure.
But wait, wait, wait.
Yeah, I'm definitely gonna buy that one.
What else do I have?
I have this one.
I have 600 gold left.
A whole second.
Oh, this casts four spells per cast as well.
Very poor mana charge speed.
So is that one.
Oh man.
These are kind of bad ones.
I mean, I'll buy that one.
But hold on.
Let's put this stuff up here.
So, plasma beam does 20 damage.
How fast does that damage happen is the question.
Wait, what does this cast always?
Wait a minute.
Aiming arc.
A projectile rotates towards the direction you're aiming.
So like...
If I were to do this.
Oh yeah.
That's not bad.
Oh, but it's so slow.
If only it had some speed.
What is a better example?
Hmm.
Maybe that one.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
I think if anything, I should put this on a trigger.
Just to be safe.
Because this can 100% damage myself.
Which is no bueno.
What else can I buy here?
Oh yeah, right, this one.
Bunch of chainsaws.
Do I even need that many?
I don't need this many of these, obviously.
Let's just throw away a bunch.
I'll keep one of these.
I'll take some more.
Or just leave these on this one for now.
If only I could find a trigger right now.
Then I could make something really nice.
How much money do I have?
$375.
I could buy this one, because this is basically a trigger.
And it's energy sphere.
That's digging.
That's actually big.
I have to get this one.
This is actually a sick wand as well.
Look at the castile and recharge time.
That is not bad.
Gimme.
Oh wait, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, wait.
This is not the digging one.
This is the other one.
What was the other one called?
Wait, is it really not?
Hmm.
But watch this.
Oh, the mana...
Wait.
Hold up a second.
Okay, nevermind, nevermind.
So, I can put this on a...
So this is a trigger, basically.
What if I try this?
Ah, shit.
Go!
Okay.
Yeah, I don't know about that.
It seems to be a little random where that aims.
So maybe if I had a...
What do you call it?
Homing on it.
Maybe that could work.
I wonder how that's gonna work with a plasma beam, and not a projectile that flies through the air.
I guess I can experiment with it.
But what I want is basically a double scatter on this chainsaw.
Because what happens is, this gets shot, right?
When it impacts, it's gonna shoot two chainsaws.
And both of these do 13 damage.
That is actually a respectable amount of damage here.
Look, 35.
We went from 5 to 35.
Not bad at all.
And I could also try...
What if I just throw these on here?
All right, it costs way more mana, because that's the good thing about the chainsaws, is that they're essentially free.
They only have one mana.
Oh, I can do something like this.
Oh, dude.
One, two.
There.
That should work.
Oh, boy, it works.
That's incredible.
I think I'm starting to understand how to make some good ones here, out of very simple things.
I'm gonna keep these as well.
The spark bolts.
What do I do with those?
Do we want the lightning bolt?
I mean, it is nice.
Yo.
What if we put a freeze charge?
Maybe that's even better.
Let's say we do this.
Also, I have a question here, so I need to test something real quick.
So if I do this...
Oh, wait, I can't test this like this.
I need to try with these, so I can see it.
Let me remove that one.
Okay, so that gives freeze charge on both of these, but if I do that, is it only gonna be the left one?
Wait, I couldn't quite tell.
Uh...
Oh, no!
No!
How do I get out?
Ah!
Okay, we're fine, we're fine, we're fine, we're fine, we're fine.
Oh, shit!
Imagine dying there!
I was panicking, guys.
That was really bad.
Okay, look at that.
Yeah, it definitely applies it to both still.
That kind of blows my mind.
Wait a minute.
What if I put it here?
Definitely applies it to both still.
What?
I don't understand.
Why does it do that?
Like this I understand, because you put the freeze charge, which is a modifier of a projectile.
What do you modify?
This guy.
And this guy shoots two projectiles, so they both get affected.
But if I do this, then this modifier should only affect this guy.
No?
Apparently not!
It doesn't even matter where it is, look.
All right, well, that's good to know.
So if I do this...
Wait.
Is it still...
I can't quite tell.
Basically, it's gonna add five more damage to both of these chainsaws now.
Which is kind of...
How much damage is that now?
Oh, I'm out of mana.
It's not bad, but look, it does cost a lot of mana to cast.
So maybe instead of this, it is better to just do that.
Like in the end, the damage output is greater.
Maybe this is actually better.
I think it's very close.
And I also don't like the freeze charge, because...
Well, actually...
No, no, no, it actually is good.
It's gonna freeze enemies, and that is very good.
Then I can tablet them afterwards.
In fact...
Okay, I'm sacrificing my life here.
Oh, wait, can I even dig?
Maybe I can with plasma beam.
Actually, I don't think I can.
I tried that once.
Everything is just frozen now.
I don't know what to do.
I guess it's nice to have like, just like a chainsaw spammer.
Right?
Maybe that's better.
No, it's worse.
It's even worse.
What if I add more?
Oh, yeah!
Oh, wow!
More?
Oh, that's pretty much...
...that's really nice.
So if I go... if someone comes close to me, I go brrrr!
And they're gone.
That could be nice.
But then again, I also want to replace all these wands.
So maybe I'll just leave it, you know?
Although we gotta do some digging, so we still need these.
Maybe it's better down here now.
Okay, so watch, but now it's so slow, we add this.
Does it not make it better?
Okay, it doesn't do shit for some reason.
Uh, hold on.
Maybe if we add that.
Oh, yeah!
Much better!
What if we do two of them and only one?
That may even be better.
It's hard to say, though.
I think I like that.
That's our digging wand!
That's the digger right there.
Plasma beam.
Yo, what if we...
Nah, nah, nah, nah.
That's not good too crazy here.
I... I'm definitely gonna kill myself if I'm not too careful.
Okay, I'm gonna have two empty wands so I can replace them.
That's the plan.
Now, I could buy this as...
I cannot buy that because I don't have enough money.
But this one, I don't want to buy it.
No.
Let's go!
If I had a way to get out of here, I would make him mad right now.
And kill him.
But, uh...
Nope.
Not right now.
Let's see how this works.
Not bad.
They definitely get frozen.
Large spitter bolt with timer.
Yeah.
That actually has a lot of...
uh...
mana charge speed.
That could be really interesting to play with.
In fact, let me go back immediately.
Shit.
Actually, no.
Let me explore just a bit more.
I gotta wait for that.
Again?
Okay, that's fine.
I'll take it.
Another...
Ooh, nice, nice, nice.
Hey, nice.
Fly downwards.
Man, this wand is also kind of sick with the mana charge speed.
Oh, but it casts two spells per cast.
I feel like I should also experiment with these types of wands.
I don't think I quite understand this.
I gotta be honest.
The number of spells this wand casts when used is two.
Like, I think I understand it.
I'm not entirely sure.
I gotta experiment.
Ah, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
Oh.
Oh, the mana charge speed on this wand is gonna kill me.
It's really bad.
It's blocking?
What do you mean?
It's a terrible wand!
I fucked up, guys.
I made a shitty wand.
I think it's because these guys are mechanical, and Chainsaw's not doing anything to them.
Hey, come here.
Help me.
Help me against this dude over here.
Go.
All right, you can also kill those.
That's...
No, friendo!
You bastard!
I actually took damage from touching his corpse because it was so cold.
I think I should have my lightning bolt.
Very nice.
I'm good at killing snipers.
Oh, shit.
Oh, this is...
I'm actually...
I'm dead.
I'm getting my ass kicked.
I...
It's over.
Go.
Go!
Leave!
Aw, this is horrible, guys.
I'm...
I'm playing so bad.
It's actually over.
Why is everything on fire?
Oh, no.
Oh, it's over.
I can't.
Yeah.
That was a shit run, anyway.
I didn't find anything.
I was low all the time.
It was bad.
That was a bad run.
Also, I feel like the wand I made really sucked ass.
I needed to go back to the drawing board with that one.
That was a major disaster.
I should have just kept my lightning bolt.
You know, the tried and true.
What the hell is this?
Aha!
Well...
Excuse me.
Wow.
There we go.
I am getting high.
Immediately.
We gotta lick our wounds after that last run there.
And it is Little Friday, after all.
Oh, yeah.
Eat all that.
Delicious.
Is this gonna be enough?
Oh, I'm puking now.
Oh, this is bad.
Oh, yeah.
You heard the word smoke echoing and shifting in colors.
Oh, did I just take a lot of HP?
Like, damage there?
Oh, God.
Uh-oh.
Oh, wait.
I can't dig anymore.
I was still in the last mindset.
With the previous run.
So, wait, smoke?
Hold on.
Smoke.
Wait, smoke?
I can make smoke.
I forget if something became smoke or smoke became something else.
I honestly, I can never remember.
I just can't.
If I blow up the water, that's gonna produce...
Oh, no.
Wait, has smoke become...
flammable gas?
Is that what's happening here?
That does not look good.
This guy right here is an asshole.
I'm gonna keep my distance and just keep plinking away at him.
There we go.
That worked pretty well.
Solid.
I think smoke has become flammable gas.
Because look at all the flammable gas everywhere, where there's fire.
Like what produces smoke?
Fire, right?
Oh, yeah, look.
Oh, wait, acid.
No, smoke has become acid.
Which then turns into flammable gas.
Oh, no.
That's terrible.
But you know what?
I am pretty convinced that if we get high again...
everything will be okay.
The only solution is to get more high.
So basically, if it says smoke...
it means smoke became something else.
So the word that comes up on screen is the thing that's changing.
But we don't know what it's changing into.
Don't forget it.
Remember it.
Okay, nah.
I can't get up there.
Ah!
I can do that though.
Man, this acid is going to be an issue, isn't it?
I have mud on me.
Not exactly inspiring a lot of confidence in myself.
I need to grab some water instead.
Mud is just not going to do it for me.
Look at that.
I'm making a mountain of mud.
I feel like that guy from Close Encounters of the Third Kind right now, making this sort of...
needs to be more flat on the top.
Something like that.
I've seen this in my dreams.
Look at that.
Beautiful.
Oh man, mushrooms keep growing?
Guess I'll be back here later to get high again.
Oh crap, can't get up there.
I think I lost a lot of HP eating those mushrooms just before.
Fuck me, I can't go anywhere.
Guess I'll go right.
See what's over there.
Maybe we'll find a wand.
Go.
Oh, that's a bad idea.
No, there's nothing that way anyway, so let's not go.
Hamis.
Oh!
Wow, that exploded quick.
That was a trap, man.
Talk about pouring salt in the wound here.
I'm already suffering.
Why you got to make it worse like that?
Berserkium though, now that's what I'm talking about.
Drink some of it.
Nice.
So it seems that acid by itself just simply evaporates.
Like you don't even need to do anything to it, it just evaporates.
I mean, I guess I already knew that, but I think it's very confirmed at this point.
What happens if I pour this on gunpowder?
Nothing.
Gotta try things, right?
Ah, I need water.
No, I can go from above.
Sir?
Damn!
Did he explode because of the transformation that we have?
Maybe acid makes them explode.
Okay, tablet for me.
Nice.
300 monies?
That's not enough.
I would ideally like more.
And some more hearts.
What is that?
Oh, it's coal.
All right, clear.
Oh, I wand.
That's what I need, baby.
I predict there will be a teleport in this wand.
Whoa!
I guarantee there was a teleport in there.
I mean, trust me, there was a teleport in that wand.
You know what happened there?
The smoke became acid and I died immediately.
That's what happened.
I was so confused why that was exploding like that, but it actually makes sense.
Oh, man.
That was a funny death, actually.
Can I even make it up here?
Curse the gods.
Made it.
I don't know if that spark bolt helped, but I don't care.
Maybe it did a little bit.
Man, look how blue it is!
This is very blue.
Oh, shit.
I thought I had a magic missile.
Wait a bit.
Perfect shot.
There we go.
Perfect start.
And we have water.
Everything is in order.
Wow, a lot of water, actually.
Why is it raining so much?
Okay, I'm back, bitches.
This time, this is the run, guys.
This is the one.
I just had to get a couple warm-up rounds in there, okay?
Now we're back on track.
This is the one.
I will defy all odds.
Because look at that, we already have a wand ready for us.
And I need to play more safe.
I have to remember, I have a tablet now.
And I'm actually not afraid to use it either.
Beautiful.
I can get in there easy.
Oh, come on.
Dang it!
Oh, wait, that was immaculate.
Fuck yeah.
I love me some energy spheres.
It's my favorite.
Shit, I should have used my tablet.
Like, if there's easy targets...
So, the tablet should be used on very easy targets or very hard targets.
And the in-between is like the wand.
That's the way I'm seeing that.
Oh, god.
I wanted to grab the tablet, but I thought this was my tablet, but it was to the left of me.
I was bamboozled.
Oh, god.
I gotta water this.
No, the money.
My precious money.
Special delivery.
Oh, wow.
It blocked his shot.
Did you see that?
Hey, man, this thing can really kill even at slow speeds.
Nice.
Oh, it killed someone else on the way down.
Lovely.
Incredible.
I'm getting better with the tablet.
Ooh, the fireball.
This time, I don't have that stupid transformation, so everything is okay.
Oh, yeah, you want some?
You know what?
The tablet is actually also very good at killing enemies in a...
What do you call it?
Clean way.
Because when you shoot them, oftentimes, they'll bleed, right?
And if that's the acid people, the bleeding is unstoppable, and it just becomes horrible to deal with.
I can get through there.
Can I do with fire, though?
Not really.
But it's good against the wood.
There's a wand.
Uh-oh.
That's electricity.
Let me see here.
I think the best way is just blow this up immediately.
Crap.
Oh, fuck.
That thing's going to blow, though, right?
Actually, maybe it's fine.
All this oil is going to go away, and that's totally cool.
There we go.
Dispose stuff safely.
Shielding.
That wand is pretty good.
Man, if only that was a non-shuffle.
Actually, maybe just replace this one.
Disturb the water.
Now, this hemisphere is going well.
Not like the others today.
But now I have my warm-up, so...
It's to be expected.
What's happening?
This guy has a wand.
Um...
Come at me, bruh.
It's a nice little perimeter to make.
The circle of shielding.
You just hang back there.
Have some fun.
Crack open a cold wand.
And shoot him up.
Watch this.
That's what that is for.
That is art.
Actually, the gold.
Yeah, I made it.
Nice.
So, look at this right here.
I feel like there's a puzzle right there somehow.
I just can't figure it out.
There's a small hole.
Maybe something needs to go on top of here.
Ah, I can't figure it out, man.
It's very striking.
Oi!
Shit!
Good to have a backup.
See what's up here.
Fuck, I should have used my tablet there.
That would have been double the money.
You know what?
There's actually a connection with tablets and money in general.
Also, because when you put a tablet on the altar up in the sky, you get money out of it, right?
And when you kill enemies with a tablet, you get also money there.
Like, money seems to be intimately tied to the...
Whoever wrote these tablets somehow.
Uh-oh.
Oh.
Why did I just pour water on that?
That's the worst thing I could have done!
Gimme!
There we go.
Should I go down there?
No, but I can put it on fire.
Always makes me happy.
There's oil in here.
Oh, is that gonna go all the way around, probably?
Let me get rid of this thing.
That works.
Look at that.
The energy sphere.
Oh, look at it.
Look at this, guys.
It's gonna be so much money.
Huh!
All right, that's fine.
We definitely made more money than we otherwise would have.
It was good.
I thought it would roll through all of them.
But I guess crashing into one of them stopped the momentum a little bit.
Oh, shit!
I apologize!
Sorry, Hemis.
I promise I will pet your friends later on.
For what I've done.
This place always looks like a bunch of, uh, a bunch of acid.
Ate through here.
Had to do it.
That was a bit risky.
Oh, wow.
All right, let's go west.
So far, so good.
Circle of shielding.
Actually, solid arsenal that I have.
Nice!
That's what I'm talking about.
Did I hear a shotgun man?
Through here.
Nope.
Let me go top.
Just do that.
Water me.
It's a good habit to water yourself a little bit first.
Fuck, this is a dead end.
Very unexpected.
All right, I guess we're going here.
That was perfectly embedded.
Ha!
A chest with gold.
That's a bit too risky, I think.
Oh, look at this.
It's gonna be the ultimate slaughter.
Oh, come on.
Oh, shit.
That was a lot of money.
That just made me rich.
And a chainsaw!
Hell yeah!
That's really good.
Very good start.
Get some water.
Oh, man.
Okay, so here's the plan.
I'm gonna conserve my health.
I mean, obviously.
But the idea is, I want to have like, minimum something like 70 in the next stage.
And the reason is, I can...
Hold on, I need to think.
Yeah.
If I can find more hearts in the next stage, and then go back and heal, I essentially heal more, right?
Maybe it's a bit too...
I don't know.
Naive to assume that I can survive.
But I think it's not a bad idea.
I mean, it depends how well it goes here, of course.
And I'm not done here.
What is that?
Oh.
That looked interesting.
Look at that.
Pipes.
There's the smell of gas in the air.
Ooh.
I don't like that.
If you smell gas in your house, it's time to vent out immediately.
That's very bad.
I wonder what that actually means, gameplay-wise, is, can I not use any fire at all?
Is that gonna...
fucking blast things?
I mean, there's fire here.
I'm probably okay.
Anyone down here?
Oh yeah, I see you.
Oh, there we go.
Lovely that.
That's lovely.
Boink!
The tablet man.
Strikes again.
Oh, this guy needs to die.
To the tablet, too.
Oh, bitch!
That was awesome!
Whoops, wrong one.
Didn't mean to throw that bomb, but okay, that worked out.
Ho!
Blow that up.
Yeah!
I feel like I'm playing quite well right now.
It's not a...
It's not a jinx.
What is that stuff right here?
Are those letters?
Hold on.
I want to tell me what that is.
Can I eat it?
Hold on, let's wait for the fire.
No, I can't eat it.
The fire's gonna...
give me damage.
Let's wait a bit.
Whoa!
Shit.
Oh, god.
This is bad.
What else do I have?
I have one dynamite.
Okay.
Is that all acid?
It is.
Shit.
Fuck me.
Wait, will the acid dissolve my tablet?
Doesn't seem like it.
I think we're okay.
Oh, man.
That was a little too risky.
Yeah, look at these pipes.
They're all emitting gas.
It's real bad.
Is that molten metal?
It is.
No, nowhere is safe.
Oh!
Worm pheromone.
All right.
Nothing over there.
I have to remember, I have circle of shielding.
I keep forgetting.
That's honestly one of my weaknesses.
I pick things up and I forget I have them.
Like, it's so good.
It's so good.
Oh, that's all flammable.
Not set it on fire.
Let's not do that.
Shit, oh shit, oh shit, oh shit.
Playing it safe, playing it safe.
Ah, ah, turn it into water.
Wait in the water.
Now, do I have any vision?
Maybe this one makes vision.
Nope.
Does not look like it.
Can't get through there.
Look how long these last as well.
Oh, this is a tablet.
Come on.
I dare you, boy.
Shit.
Roll downhill.
Oh, man.
Throwing cocktails.
Oh, Molotov cocktails.
I get it now.
That actually makes a lot of sense.
Oh, come on.
There we go.
How am I not on fire?
You.
Hey, sick.
Oh, a chest as well.
What is the best way in there?
Probably from above.
I have one dynamite.
If I place it absolutely perfectly in this little thingy here.
Oh, okay, not bad.
But now we need...
Oh, wait, chainsaw.
Chainsaw, I forgot about that.
It actually digs.
It's a wand.
A digging wand.
With a fireball orbit.
How about no.
I will kill myself with that.
I guarantee it.
Do not use it.
I don't want to use that.
Although, does that produce light in the cave?
Oh, the circle of shielding just popped out of existence.
All right, we have done our job.
It's time to get a move on.
Next area.
We do not take the health.
Okay, okay.
Oh, that's not bad.
That's really good.
What is that one?
Oh, this is the one-off health thing.
I mean, I think I would rather just re-roll.
Oh, wow.
And good fucking thing I did.
Wow.
You cannot be mad about that.
Holy shit.
We have teleport now.
We have everything.
In fact, put this here.
And this was a good wand, right?
No, 10 mana charge.
That one sucks.
Throw it away.
This was the good wand.
It's shuffle, but you can probably shoot it, like, in an insane way here.
Look at this.
Oh, it's like it's number three here, so I assumed it was keybind three, but it's actually on four, so it gets moved up here.
That's a bit weird, isn't it?
Yeah.
It's not bad.
Although it is limited by...
Do they add castellate?
They do.
That's why.
Okay.
All right.
Let's see what else I can do.
Black hole.
We got to go with that one, obviously.
That means we can make a steward mad.
We can kill him.
Wait, we don't need to do that.
We can edit wands everywhere.
We don't need to bother with that shit.
Fuck yeah.
Oh, that's awesome.
That's what this does.
That's how powerful that is.
What else do I want?
Always casts, I think, fire trail?
Yeah.
Trail of fiery particles.
It has light on it, which is actually very nice.
Dude, you know what I could do?
Oh, but hold on.
We got to make steward mad at some point, because if I want to go back up, it needs to happen anyway.
Right?
I was about to say, maybe I'll just make the black hole up, go back to the first area, and go to the cave, and light it up now that I have light.
Let me think about this.
What should I make?
Do I have any triggers at all somewhere?
I do not think so, but I have this.
And we definitely need that.
This is a shuffle.
I mean, I don't even know.
We don't need this many.
That's bad.
Whoa.
Wait, why does it do that?
Fuck!
Why didn't I think about that?
Dang it.
Yeah, it's solid.
It's a solid teleport.
It's a good teleport.
Maybe it's a bit too quick.
I think I may like this more.
Like, if it's too quick, it's a little bit...
You know?
In fact, that's the perfect sweet spot there.
That's the speed I like.
Love that speed.
So for the actual damage now, I think a double is always good to have.
I guess the triple is always good to have as well.
But this one is a no...
Oh, this one is...
Not the worst.
Give me that one.
Yeah.
Wait, .05.
Wait a minute.
Oh, that one cast three...
Oh, because it spells per cast six.
Hold up.
That another circle of shielding?
Okay.
No way.
Huh?
Why was that there?
Oh, because I took the double.
I'm an idiot.
Right.
Okay, that's not bad.
But look at that.
We need recharge.
We need less recharge.
And we can do that with that.
Reduces recharge time.
Not bad.
Helps a little bit.
But if we do...
Okay, hold up.
If we do...
Can we double dip?
It's double dippy do time.
Like we do this?
Uh, hold on.
Is that double dipping?
One?
What?
It's not.
Wait.
Why not?
Why are we not double dipping?
Chainsaw.
Huh.
I was thinking it shoots.
You want chainsaw?
You know, we get the recharge time effect.
The reduction.
It shoots.
It shoots this, which shoots too.
Which is that one.
And what's the next?
That one.
AKA double dippy do.
But there's no double dippy do here.
Not that I can see.
How come it never shoots the single chainsaw?
I actually don't understand that.
Where is the singular chainsaw?
Uh, hold on.
In fact, the chainsaw doesn't even shoot in this configuration.
Okay, so there it is.
Chainsaw there.
Easy.
Now these two should shoot a chainsaw and then a spitter bolt.
Oh, you know what?
I think it is.
It's just so fast you don't see it.
Because look at the wand.
You can see the effect.
It's so fast.
You can't see it on the board.
And I...
And you know what?
That's because the castile is so low.
It's 0.1 seconds.
And it's even being reduced by 0.02.
So that's why it's so quick.
What if I do this?
Oh, interesting.
Now it's more obvious.
It shoots the spitter bolt and then it shoots the chainsaw.
So interestingly, it looks like the castile is actually higher now.
You see that?
Before it was so low, you couldn't even see.
Look at the difference.
We are limited by recharge time now, but these two spells here are being cast so quickly that it looks like it's in one instant.
But like this, you can tell there's a little bit of a longer delay and it's also visible on the board.
So I guess it is being shot.
Maybe we are double dibby doing here.
I'm just not realizing it.
Because if I do that and I do this...
Look how much slower it is.
Yeah, we're definitely double dibby doing here.
This is a DDD.
Confirmed.
And we have teleport, that's nice.
But the question is, is this even a good wand?
I mean, I was just experimenting here.
Probably a shit wand anyway.
So we need digging now.
Energy sphere is not it.
It is kind of cool that it shoots three at a time.
But if I do this, it doesn't really do much.
Unless I double dibby do it again.
It's a little better, I think.
What reduces cast delay?
I guess these do.
Maybe it'll just be boring.
I mean, it works.
It's not fantastic or anything.
And then we double dip this one.
No, wait, it goes here.
Definitely faster.
I think that's a solid wand.
I like it.
And we can do digging.
Oh, that's a solid digging wand!
Wow!
Holy shit.
Because look at the recharge time on it.
Very nice.
And we have black hole.
Okay, not bad.
Then I have this stuff as well.
I'm gonna buy it.
It's no shuffle.
It's two spells per cast.
You know what?
I'm gonna take this opportunity to try and understand the two spells per cast.
I need to get to the bottom of this.
In fact, this one reduces cast delay by 0.03.
It has a very high speed as well.
Wait a minute.
Let me see this.
In fact, I have two of these, right?
So why don't I just do that?
One, two, one.
Wait.
Didn't we have a triple?
Shit, I don't have money.
Ah, crap.
I mean, not that I want a triple, I guess, because it's gonna shoot it everywhere.
Well, the recharge time is the limiting factor here now.
It's a little better now.
I think I like that.
Maybe it's just better if I just...
just stock up the old way here.
A bit of that.
That's pretty solid.
But we're limited by recharge.
And I don't have anything that reduces recharge.
I could put a light.
Wait, can I double DB do with this?
Let me see.
Oh yeah, I'm double DB doing.
Look at that.
Wait.
So, chainsaw?
Wait, am I?
Wait, no, I'm not.
I'm not.
No, wait, I am.
I am.
It's just so fast you don't see it.
I'm definitely.
This is a double dip.
It's just, it just doesn't do much.
And we get light on it now.
No, we don't.
We only get light on the chainsaw.
Or maybe if we use a double here.
There we go.
Much better.
Now we have damage.
We have teleport.
Put this here.
Put this... yeah, that's fine.
We can put some of these here as well.
Don't need that many.
Put this one here.
No, wait, we need that one.
There we go.
You know, I could put it...
Oh, it's shuffle, never mind.
Put this up here.
Now the last wand is a double spells per cast.
So let's see here.
If I do this, that's gonna cast both of them with one click.
Right?
Oh, shit!
Right, it has a fiery trail.
Yeah, I don't, I don't like that.
No.
I need fire resistance for that stuff.
I'm gonna replace this wand.
All right, we have a good setup.
Let's go.
Wait, we have black hole?
Should I put that somewhere?
Uh...
Hmm.
Ah, shit.
I will leave it as is for now.
Yeah, I just need to find better wands.
That's really all it is.
And we have good digging capabilities, so the air feels light.
What does that mean?
Wait, does that mean what I think it means?
Like, less of a drop off on spells?
Whoa!
Wow.
Whoa, that was a bit risky on my part there.
That was bad.
I have to remember, I have teleport now.
Uh...
Oh, that was mine.
I'm not terribly happy about the bounding burst.
But I'm very happy about this digging wand.
Oh, wait, that doesn't get destroyed by that?
No way.
Are you kidding me?
Holy shit, man.
That was an Ukuskivian in there.
What the hell?
Are you actually kidding me?
That's so unlucky.
I tried to be safe about it too, you know?
By shooting the chest first, but I was still in the water in that split second.
Man, oh man.
I wasn't fast enough.
In fact, new rule.
When the chest is in the water, obviously we shoot the chest.
But never try to do it from underwater.
Like, you don't have time to get out.
You always have to shoot your shot outside of the water.
Because it is literally instant.
That electricity spreads so quick.
Oh, that's a lot of polymorphine.
I'm gonna blow it up.
Wait, what?
There's no trap.
I guess the polymorphine is the trap.
Question is, where should I drain it?
Probably over here.
Sweet.
Get rid of it.
What do I have?
Swap potion.
That's fine.
I can probably take that now.
That's terrible.
But it's actually better than I think it is.
It's a decent wand for now.
Yeah, I like it.
You're about to take my wand.
I'm actually getting my ass kicked today.
This is insane.
I'm really getting punished.
Now you probably understand why I don't want to start Nightmare yet.
I can't even play the game on normal.
If this isn't proven enough, then I don't know what is.
Nice!
A heart!
And I have plenty of explosions.
Wait, I thought it would blow up the bottom part too here.
Because, oh, I guess that makes sense.
I guess the steel wall must have absorbed the explosion from here.
From that angle.
Didn't consider it.
Let me put one right here.
That should do it.
Nice.
Very good.
Berserkium.
Yes, please.
Have some of that.
I don't know why it's called a Berserk curse.
Like, what is the downside to it?
I only see upsides.
Maybe it's like, oh, you're too strong.
You know, like you will destroy things without knowing it.
Like you don't know your own strength type of thing.
I just don't see how that's a bad thing.
It should not be a curse.
It should be called a blessing.
A blessing of Berserk affects you.
What do we have?
Nice.
Yeah.
Dope.
You know what that means, right?
We can go into the dark cave.
It's draining time.
And you know how I love to drain.
I want.
That's not bad.
Right?
Oh, I guess the recharge is kind of shit.
But look at the mana charge speed on it.
I mean, there's only two slots, but you can definitely make something very mana intensive with that.
Like something that costs a lot of mana.
It's a potential digging wand candidate.
But you would have to get rid of the recharge.
Yeah.
And that's easier said than done.
With two slots.
Hey, dude!
Hand over your money.
Uh, that's a dead end.
I could use a black hole, but I'm not gonna.
Dude, you know what?
One of the main priorities I need to have in this game is actually to go to the ancient laboratory and kill that boss.
Because that shit breaks the whole game.
Like as soon as I'm powerful enough, I actually need to go there.
That needs to be my...
Like, I need to know my power level, like when I'm strong enough for that.
I gotta figure out some kind of consistent way to kill that boss.
Get his spells and become completely and utterly broken.
Jesus Christ, my dude.
Thank you.
Ow!
Fuck you!
Unreal.
Still.
Flamoxium.
Should I... yeah, I'll take it.
Let's try and pour some on the enemies.
As though he's confused now.
What does it do?
Oh, I thought maybe he would attack his friends.
Wait!
Huh?
I thought for sure that barrel was gonna explode in my face, but instead it became a bush.
The fuck is that?
Some divine power is looking out for me right now.
Oh, you guys want fire?
Nothing like burned frocks.
Normally I like frocks, but in this game I kind of hate them.
That...
Whatever want there.
He killed his friend!
You're not even dead yet.
Oh my god.
All right.
Yeah, this one is not that great.
Gotta be honest here.
How are you not dead yet?
Oh no.
I need my tablet!
Sir!
Fuck you.
Is he gonna burn alive?
Haha!
Uh-oh, uh-oh, uh-oh, uh-oh!
Ho ho!
Oh shit!
Got him.
Oh no, all the money.
Fuck.
Okay.
I can get to that health in there.
I think.
Whoops.
Here I can prop...
Oh, wait!
I don't...
Wait.
This digs.
Fuck!
I don't have money for the black hole.
I mean, mana.
Why didn't I think about that?
I was operating under the assumption that I had enough.
Oh, but never mind.
I do!
Let's go.
What do you say to that?
Drain it.
I may just take this just to have one more.
I do like the magic bolt.
Now I'm keeping the magic bolt.
I feel like a wand with that could be insane.
Wait a minute.
Is there a worm here?
Look at this.
This is totally the work of a worm.
Oh no.
Tell me it's dead.
We're done.
That's it.
It's over.
I need to find a tablet immediately.
It's the only real option I have.
And then hope to god I can kill him with one hit.
I gotta pull out some special strats here.
Also, can I get rid of this damn mud or whatever it is?
I need proper water.
Don't care for swamp.
There we go.
So how do I do this?
What I could do is go to the mountain.
Hopefully get a...
Hopefully get a chain bolt.
Because that's a certified way of doing it.
Then I use a black hole and I use a tablet.
To block myself in.
That's the proven strategy.
But if I can't do that...
It's tablet time.
And I just, I can't miss.
It needs to be the perfect throw.
There you are, you fucker.
Well, you already did the...
You already made a mess, didn't you?
Oh, but you know what?
I can drink the shit and go into the cave.
But he's gone now.
He went down there.
Oh god.
Maybe this is better.
I don't like my primary wand.
I need to empty this one.
And get some worm blood.
Drink the, uh, persecium.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Not bad, not bad.
Doing some good damage here.
How are you not dead?
There we go.
Beautiful.
And now we empty this.
We get the worm blood.
If we're going to have any chance against Stewart, we're going to need more HP.
Get in here.
So I have...
That's fine.
Pick it up.
Oh yeah.
Oh yeah, that's it.
That's it.
There's worm pheromone here.
Alright, let's go pick up a tablet.
Oh my god.
I got him.
Not bad.
I still have two black holes left.
Oh, that's a lot of water.
You know what, I kind of want to blow up and make all this into, uh, stone.
Hold on.
Can I?
Nah, it's not that easy.
It does actually kind of spread in there, look.
Shit, shit.
That was a bit too close there.
Alright, here we are.
So what am I going to throw away?
Probably the unstable teleport.
Let's put it down gently.
Fuck!
I put it down gently!
Oh man.
What is this?
That was honestly funny.
I can't be mad.
That was funny.
Fucking into the lava.
That's the worst.
I don't think that's ever happened to me.
That's a first.
Holy shit.
Yikes.
I have a newfound fear of unstable teleportation, guys.
That was bad.
That was not good.
Oh, this is going to take 1.4 million years.
I gotta wait a bit.
That one.
Be patient.
Not!
What a scam.
Blood.
I mean, I would love that if I was a vampire.
Hello?
I guess I'm hitting it at an angle.
It needs to be straight on.
There.
There we go.
So imagine a tangent.
The opposite of that.
Perpendicular is the word.
Go!
Okay, it's stuck now.
I will take it, though.
Yes.
If we can get the tablet as well, that would be wonderful.
Nah, that's going to take too long.
I will grab the other tablet.
Speaking of the tablets.
I need to bring them around with me everywhere and sort of put them on certain things.
Because those are like, consistent items that do something when you put them somewhere.
I need to put them more places.
Especially in enemy's faces.
And I need to tie my laces.
I'm sorry.
Oh, I have the bouncing burst!
It's the worst spell in the game!
It's not, but it's close.
What is the worst spell in the game?
Would love to have a tablet right about now.
Okay, it's not so bad.
This is quite smooth.
I think next time I'm gonna put down a unstable teleportation gently.
I'm actually gonna throw it.
Into the lava!
Cast it into the fire!
What's that?
Flammoxium.
What is it with the flammoxium?
Oh, but you know what?
I did want to try and mix things.
Let's just try it.
How about, okay.
We try oil, blood, and flammoxium.
What happens?
No way!
Wait, runestone of weight!
What the fuck is that?
Guys, I made unstable polymorphine!
Look!
It's totally mixing!
Oh wait, runestone of weight.
Oh!
Oh my god, I'm blind.
I didn't even see that.
I thought it was behind this polymorphine.
All right, get it.
Come on.
Quick.
Go!
Got it.
Doesn't the runestone of weight kind of look like it has a face?
Similar to this.
Hold on.
It's like a very evil face.
It goes like this.
Doesn't it look like that here?
Like, look at it.
So it's an evil boy.
I think so.
Okay, so I successfully did something with liquids.
Very cool.
So, you know what?
We're gonna be making a cookbook here.
I will format this a little more pretty later.
But I'm gonna do something like...
Hold on.
We're gonna say...
Cookbook.
If we put blood...
Blood.
Plus...
What was it?
Flammoxium.
Plus...
What was the last one?
Blood, flammoxium, and oil.
Oops, can't spell.
That equals...
unstable polymorphine.
Very cool.
I need to try other things.
I wonder if it's always three things.
No, that's not true.
Because...
Toxic...
Oh, I can write this right now.
I know this one.
Toxic sludge.
Plus...
Uh, water?
Simply equals water.
Cool.
And we go back.
Yep, just keep writing shit down.
So we don't forget.
Hey, miss.
Oh, you there.
What is your name?
I need to figure out your name.
I can call you by your name.
Stendati.
All right.
Oh, you know what?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
We're grabbing the tablet.
It's tablet time.
Stendati?
Let me kill you first.
Yo, Stendo, friendo.
Oh, he died in the water.
No, the money.
Oh, that sucks.
Ha ha.
The tablet technique, TT, can't be beaten.
Okay, so I tried those three.
What else can I try?
You know what?
I should try to mix powders with liquids, too.
There's got to be something happening there, right?
Or like any material that I can put in a pouch.
And not just in a flask.
Let's be careful.
That could be a death inside of there.
Death itself could be hanging out.
Come on, Wood.
Money.
Okay, blot myself.
Go.
Oh, nice.
That was pretty sweet.
333 gold.
Hamis.
Money.
That was risky on my part there.
It really was.
So was this.
Oh my god, this health.
Awesome.
That's big.
I actually need some proper water here.
Whoa!
Let me empty this.
Stay bloody for a bit.
Kill the enemies.
Oh, no.
Tablet!
Shit!
Didn't work out.
Oh, but he doesn't care about me.
Oh, fuck!
Run!
That is just scary, isn't it?
What exactly was this again?
Right, it slows everything down.
But if I kick it,
turns it off.
Rune stone of weight.
Sir.
Leave me alone.
Gimme.
He has so much HP.
Okay, now I can get some water.
Let me empty my blood first.
Over here somewhere.
I'm pissing blood.
That's how much of a beating I've taken today.
He's gotta be dead soon.
There we go.
Good.
Okay, so look at this.
There's peat and water here.
Maybe that mixed with the third thing would do something.
So there's blood in there now.
Mix it up.
Does nothing.
What if we put phlamoxium in?
Okay.
All right.
Well, now we know that.
Wow!
Seemed like he was even aiming for that explosive.
Probably not though.
No, come on!
Why didn't you blow up up here?
What a scam!
I was gonna get in there to the hemises.
All right, here we go.
Oh, that's lovely.
That...
Boink!
No?
Okay.
Okay, okay, calm down, calm down, calm down.
There we go.
Nice and gentle.
Tablet to the face.
We get that extra money.
I gotta say though, the bouncing burst somehow does increase damage against the shotgun people.
At least it feels that way.
Like, it does some shitty damage, but it only needs a couple shots on those guys.
And I don't get why.
I've never... I haven't even found a wand.
Oh.
Why does it have to appear right when I complain about it?
Like the game knows.
Dynamite.
Not a terrible wand either, except there's only two slots.
Uh-oh, we've got this dude.
That works.
Definitely don't mind using a dynamite to kill him.
A broken wand!
Lovely!
Oh,
actually...
Wait a minute.
Duuuuude.
I was gonna throw away this, but wait a minute.
It's one-to-one!
Wait, I need to confirm.
It's... it's one-to-one.
Hold up.
Give me that.
I need to, uh, I need to take a picture.
Oh my god, it's so obvious!
Hold on.
Quick!
I got it.
And now?
Okay.
Dude, we found...
We found our fucking key!
I am 100% sure that is a direct one-to-one.
Because I looked at the amount of letters in the word and it corresponded one-to-one.
We know how to translate shit.
Oh my god.
That's so big!
Uh, can we stop making that noise?
Thing?
Oh man, we can make an alphabet!
Hold on, where do we have writing that we need to translate?
All kinds of places.
It's gonna take a bit of time, I guess.
I gotta, I gotta...
Oh shit, I'm getting too excited here.
We need to, uh, calm down.
Hold up.
Let me get this wand.
Dude, I'm excited the same way I was excited in Tunic!
This feels like Tunic right now.
Ah shit, come on.
Here's one more of these.
Hey, I like that.
Thanks.
I'm actually gonna do this right now, I can't wait.
I can't wait!
Straight into this.
Uh, let me...
Can I make another...
I can, beautiful.
So, forgive me, but I have this on my phone.
I took a picture of it.
In fact, I took two, I took the before and after picture.
I'm just gonna write.
Oh man, this is gonna be hard as hell.
Uh...
Like that?
Uh, nope.
That's an eye.
If all the mountains were of silver and gold...
And then we have...
Something like that.
F.
We're gonna order these later.
Oh wait, I don't need to look between the images!
I just need to remember the sentence.
If all the mountains were of silver and gold...
If all, so this one is A.
Hold on, I need to zoom in on my phone.
This is way too small.
Okay, so it's like...
Nope.
This is a little bit challenging.
I'm holding the phone with my left hand and riding with my right.
If all the...
This is A.
Yeah, look, and there's two...
Oh, it's totally one-to-one.
There's two of these.
And that's an L.
If all the...
This is a T.
Oh, wait a minute!
I recognize this!
Hold on.
That's a T.
That's a terrible T.
The.
That's an H.
Oh, man.
Colon.
Is an E.
No, wait, wait, wait.
If all...
Oh, no, no, no, no!
It's gotta be a...
Wait a minute.
I'm seeing this wrong.
This is one character.
T-H-E.
This is H.
That's E.
If all the...
How am I...
If all the mountains...
Is this sort of a weirdy?
M.
And then we have an O.
Dude, it was right in front of my face.
And do you know what the funny thing is?
I haven't said this out loud, but every time I encountered something in the world, like with regarding the text, I was like looking for something one-to-one like this.
I never thought about the tablets, really.
I thought it was just a, you know, neat animation to be like, oh, here's translation.
It's literally the translation.
And then we have a U.
And the U is like this.
I gotta be careful not to repeat.
M-O-U-N.
N.
And then we have T again.
Yep, don't need to repeat that.
And then we have A.
And we have I, which is sort of, is an exclamation mark.
That's funny.
Mount E-N.
Yes.
Oh, it makes total sense.
It's directly one-to-one.
And we have sort of a cross.
Hold on, I can make that better.
Mountain, that's an S.
And then, what was the full sentence?
If all the mountains were of silver and gold, were of silver and gold.
If all the mountains were.
So we have a weird...
almost like a, um, like a plus.
Am I seeing that right?
It's gotta be like that.
So this one is, if all the mountains were, this W.
And then we have an E.
The E's easy to remember.
That's just a circle.
Yeah, E again.
Oh man.
Oh wait, I don't need to repeat the E, of course.
Hold on, I'm done.
Remove it.
R, I didn't have that before.
If all the mountains were off, the O we already have, the F we already have.
That's that one.
Oh, hold on.
That one.
Oh, my hand is hurting from holding this phone.
Hold on.
If all the mountains were off, silver.
Let me see.
We don't have V.
It's a question mark.
Oh, the best part is, I recognize all these symbols from the game.
So that's a V.
It's an E.
The R is this weird.
Uh, let me see.
That one.
Yeah.
Silver and gold.
D is like this weird seven with legs.
Is that right?
Something like that.
That's D.
Or silver and gold.
Oh, the gamma is a G.
The gamma.
That's an O.
We have that already.
No, wait, wait, wait.
Something's wrong.
Hold on.
If all the mountains were of silver.
Oh, wait a minute.
There's something.
Something's wrong here.
No, no, no, no.
I keep I keep seeing the colon as a simple or as a single character.
It's not.
It's combined with the line.
And G.
Oh, wait, we have it.
We have an issue.
If all the mountains were of silver.
And.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
I was looking at the wrong one.
Oh, it's a comma.
It's a comma.
So we have O L G O L D.
Comma.
So it's like.
It's a comma.
Oh, wait, that's that's a semicolon.
It makes.
I was like, there's five like symbols here.
Okay, comma.
What would W we already know?
Oh, you.
No.
Oh, it's what?
W H A T and T is the D.
Yep.
And then W O U L D.
Okay, it's time to arrange these.
Because otherwise, I can't remember what I already have and what I don't have.
A, do we have a B?
Maybe it's easier if I just do the do it like that.
Let's find the B.
B B B B B B B B.
Is I cannot be in the whole world anything better than our medicine.
The medicine.
One, two, three, four.
Number one.
It's a four.
Write it.
That's dude.
It's a B.
Okay, C.
We don't have a C yet.
Can we find it?
Which one, two, three, four.
W H I S.
Oh, yeah, we can.
It's it's sort of an S in a weird way.
It's like.
Bup, bup, bup.
That's a C.
There's not a dot there.
Let me move that.
There we go.
That's a C.
Okay.
D.
I think we have that one.
And put them like this.
C.
D.
E is a circle.
F is D.
H.
Yep.
It's actually kind of like a Lambda.
Like a Lambda that is turned around horizontally.
And then we have G.
G was...
What is G?
Let me remember.
Gamma.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G.
H is that one.
H, I, J.
We don't have a J.
It was right in front of my eyes the entire time.
Do we even have a J here?
What would they profit a man who lives in constant fear of death?
Since there cannot be in the whole world anything better than our medicine.
Oh, you know what?
I think there's a difference between...
Wait a minute, I can test.
I cannot be...
One, two, three, four.
Wait, profit a man.
Profit a...
Okay, and then that one.
Okay, so no.
There's no difference between capital and non-capital, it seems.
Because the M in medicine is the same symbol as the M in man.
Good to know.
So, A, B, C, D, F, G.
Ho, E.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Oh, no, I was looking at the I here.
Uh, I.
That one.
H, I, J.
And we don't have, we don't have a J in this text.
There's no J.
That's kind of unbelievable.
But I guess we can find more tablets.
Let me just leave that empty.
K, L.
I'm just going to leave a bit of room there.
M, N, O.
Let's put it up here.
P. Do we have a P?
P, P, P. Profit.
They profit.
It's an X.
Oh, that's more like a row.
Let me write that correctly.
There we go.
P, O, P, Q.
Oh, we don't have a Q here for sure.
R, we have that.
Let's make a room.
Let me say the F, K, H, Y, L, C, L, M, N.
O, P, Q, R, S.
T, U.
Do we have a U?
It cannot be in the whole world.
Mountains.
Of course we do.
Where's the U?
Oh, there it is.
And then we have V, W, X.
Wait, what about the I?
Wait, wait, wait, hold on.
If... wait, we have an issue.
That's... wait, what is...
Oh, never mind.
I'm an idiot.
This is not I.
It's some symbol.
I need to remind myself of that.
But whoa, what this one?
There's an issue.
We have an issue.
Mountains, M, O, U, N, T, A, I, N, S.
Oh, but hold on.
There is an issue then.
There is a difference between capital and not capital then.
This is like...
Obvious.
There is a difference.
But apparently there's an...
Wait.
There's no difference between the small M and the big M, it seems.
Maybe it's only if you start a sentence.
Because if is the very first word in this whole thing.
Interestingly...
Oh, hold on.
The title of the fucking thing.
It's all in capital too.
I, N, A, I...
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
There is a difference.
There's a difference.
Okay, hold on.
Put this back up here.
A comma can go here, I guess, for now.
Oh, that's special characters.
They go over there.
There is definitely a difference between capital letters and small...
Non-capital.
So big T is actually a D as well.
It's like a weird D.
It's like a note.
That's confusing.
Uh, that's an A.
Okay.
Taboo, and then the big...
Oh, I see now.
That is B.
In fact, I write it a little bit wrong.
It does not go through here like a four.
Okay.
We gotta add...
It stops right there, essentially.
And then we have U, which is that weird thingy.
Then we have L, capital.
Okay.
And then we have the A again.
Perfect.
That makes sense.
The arrow up is capital S!
The arrow!
And this is capital M now.
It's a bit confusing there.
That's an R.
It's a Smarragdina.
It is.
It's like a different gamma.
It's like a little more spread gamma.
G.
And then we have a D, which is like a weird...
Something like that.
Which is a little thing.
Nope.
D.
Then we have I, which is that weird thing again that we have up here.
N.
Oh, that's interesting.
And then the last one is A.
Okay!
Let's order these a little bit.
So A.
B.
C.
I don't have that.
D.
E.
I don't have that either.
P. Q.
R.
Let me just move this up.
I'm just gonna put them like this for now.
Whoops.
Q.
R.
S.
T.
So far, so good.
Look at that!
It's our key!
Fuck me.
Right in front of my eyes.
Insane.
We gotta find more tablets.
And then we gotta translate!
Oh man.
That's exciting.
Hold on, let me double check that I removed the...
I did.
Yeah.
I mean, I do have the music test.
Okay, so instead of flammoxium now, how about we run around with acceleration?
How did that not break?
I did the opposite of putting it down gently.
And then that one didn't break?
What is this?
Come on, man.
That's some bullshit.
Also, let me get back in this game.
I have an energy sphere dynamite.
Firebolt.
Right.
Okay.
In fact, energy sphere is better.
Why don't I use that?
Bomb it.
This is already a very different noiter stream than usual.
I like it though.
I'm getting that tunic feeling.
Even though I never actually...
Ho!
Oh, I don't want to spoil anything.
No, I shall not say more regarding tunic.
I should be tabletting these guys.
No, I shouldn't.
Play it safe.
We're at 60 HP.
Except this guy is easy to kill.
Managed to get a dynamite off there before he died.
Not only is the tablet a source of pure deadliness, but it is also a source of knowledge.
The pen is indeed the sword in this game.
Or more like the pen is the maze.
62... I want to get in there.
Can I get in there?
Maybe from here.
I'm gonna bounce it off here and it's gonna land here and explode.
Oh, sick!
Oh, but that's like a dead end anyway.
Never mind.
That's not gonna blow up the roots.
The roots are pretty powerful.
Is that gonna make it a...
Ah, it does light up.
I will have to drain this, if I can.
It is the way to do it without vision.
Uh-oh.
I'm gonna have to use a dynamite on that, dude.
He is too dangerous.
Look at HP on that guy.
Sup, fool?
Oh, that was beautiful.
Oh, lovely.
Ah-ha.
Very nice.
You know what, I'm not gonna do this.
It never works for me.
What I really need is vision.
So if I can find a torch or something, then I'll do it.
What's that?
Oh, it's a minecart, I think.
What's in here?
That's very mysterious looking.
Let's check it out.
Oh, never mind.
I thought it was like a closed-off little area with a secret inside.
I have 1100 gold.
It may be time to leave.
It's actually pretty...
It's going very well.
Let's just go.
It's good.
I'm not even gonna take this.
Oh, but wait!
Is this the one with the worm and steward?
No, I don't think so.
That was the last one.
Okay, I don't like any of those spells.
Ooh, the gamble!
When near danger, you sprout fungal growths and your spells home towards enemies very slightly.
Okay, we're gonna work with that.
It's an opportunity to try new perks, I guess.
I do like this one.
I like this one too.
There's some good stuff in here.
Sure.
I like that.
And do I like fireball?
Yeah, it's a good amount of damage.
It's not bad.
This one I want.
It costs 30 mana though, because it's the one with the timer on it.
Yikes.
Oh, that goes immediately.
That's not bad.
This one's a little better.
But wait a minute.
No, get rid of that one.
These fucking eggs, dude.
I don't want eggs.
Honestly,
just do that.
No, wait, it costs...
Oh, no.
That's annoying.
It cast two at once.
Maybe that's fine, when you gotta do some heavy damage, you know?
Bam.
Someone's gonna die when you do that.
And maybe that's just what the doctor ordered right now.
Actually better here.
But then this one is kind of...
No, it's fine.
That's digging.
That's my damage.
And that's also digging.
Yeah, sure.
Let's-a go.
I want to find some text now.
I want to translate.
I feel like a proper, uh, researcher in here now.
Like some kind of archaeologist.
That is uncovering hidden lore.
Nah, that's gonna take forever.
Thanks.
Whoops!
I didn't mean to do that.
But that actually worked out pretty well.
So does this hurt me?
I guess we'll find out.
Oh, that sucks so bad.
That's horrible.
I will only use that to get through areas I absolutely need to get through.
Toxic gas?
Wait, that was a bit close.
I see you.
I see a chest.
Whoa!
What?
Huh?
Oh, wait.
Is that danger?
It says when saying- Oh yeah, it is.
Oh, that's funny.
It's danger.
Sir.
Dude!
This is not that bad!
The fungal sprouts!
Okay, don't want to go that way.
Man, what the fuck is that spell called that actually digs?
It's not energy sphere, it's something else.
Energy orb, maybe?
Give me- Yoink.
Oh, here we go.
Nice.
Very nice.
I'm rewarded for my curiosity.
Should I be- Whoops!
Wrong again.
Look at this!
It keeps sprouting.
Look at my cape!
My cape is reacting violently to it.
Oh, it's spawning weird fungus!
We're gonna get high!
Eat it!
Eat the fungus!
Wait, am I taking damage?
Hmm.
Not so sure what's happening there.
He burned alive.
Now we have a portal.
Very nice.
So guys, what's happening in there?
Are you hiding a heart or something?
I don't see anything.
Seems to be good.
I wanna wait.
The portal is down here.
Sometimes there's a heart right next to the portal, so I gotta check those.
I intend to get through here.
Eh.
Didn't do enough.
Oh!
Wait, wait, wait.
There's something in there.
No, wait, don't be an idiot.
Just walk around.
I was about to blast my way through.
I caught myself before I did the dum-dum.
Uh-oh.
Oh yeah, sprout!
Sprout my little sprouties!
Dude, that's fantastic!
I actually like this a lot!
Fungal disease, man!
I am become the fungus.
Listen to me.
I'm the fun guy around here.
That guy was yellow.
Somehow.
I kinda wanna find another one of those, um...
boxes that I found with the text on.
Remember last time?
I found a box with text on it here, and then when I entered, there was a wand and some more text.
I really wanna translate that.
I wanna translate all the things.
Let's go this way.
Ah!
Can I...
I'm stuck!
There we go.
Oh my god.
47 HP.
That's borderline what I consider...
It's time to get the fuck outta here.
HP.
Like, look at this island here!
This exact tile I've seen somewhere else.
Uh-oh.
Shit!
Oh, this bat!
Please don't die now.
Fuck you!
Oh my god.
Get that money!
No, don't get the money.
Play it safe.
I just wanna get a little bit more before I leave.
Something in there.
Blast it.
Wait!
Did my dynamite follow him?
Hold on.
Oh, I have homing!
I totally forgot about that!
That explains it.
I thought it was related to the...
fuck all the seas.
Oh my god.
The homing.
I think I should leave.
Just grab this, and then I leave.
Now I leave.
Hold on.
Yep.
Oh wait, what's up here?
Why is he purple?
Okay, now I'll leave.
Sometimes there's a heart rating just around the corner.
You never know.
Gods above, please grant me a sick spell.
That's good.
Love it!
Yes!
Oh man!
Thank you, gods.
That's all I needed.
That one...
Could be cool.
I'm immune to electric.
You know what?
I should try new perks.
I'm already on a streak here of trying new things.
Let's try it.
Everything is electrified, and I'm immune.
Doesn't sound too bad.
I like it.
Okay, so I have 1000 gold.
Let's first see the ones.
Anything super amazing?
Not really.
No, it all kind of sucks.
The mana charge speed is atrocious in all of these.
This is the best there is, and it's shuffle.
Just from a pure want perspective here.
Um...
Let me take this...
This was...
Take all of these.
Teleporters...
Oh boy, that's a...
That's not a short one, though.
That's okay.
Better than nothing.
Then I definitely want this one.
Chainsaw time.
Double and lights.
Actually very lovely items here.
And that one.
My beloved.
The plasma cutter!
We're back in business.
Point one...
Oh, but look at the mana charge on that.
Oh, but wait a minute.
With a chainsaw that costs one mana?
Maybe it's okay.
If I chainsaw something...
What if I do this?
Nah, it uses...
No, this one costs 30 mana.
It's bad, it's bad.
It's terrible.
This one reduces a lot of recharge and castalay.
So this is definitely something you apply to a dummy.
The dummy technique.
What if I double this?
Right, it just makes it longer.
We're not interested in that.
That is cool, but it's too...
Shit.
Man, my wands suck!
Like, I...
I don't have the knowledge to make something great here.
I just don't know how to do it.
That's not bad.
This is my digging wand.
Digging wand achieved.
I don't know what to do.
I think my best bet is to...
I don't know.
Maybe double...
No, wait, this is a shuffle wand.
That's terrible.
Fuck, I don't know.
Maybe just something boring as that.
And we have teleport.
Let me see how good that is.
That's terrible on this one.
Let's put it on this one instead.
Much better.
That's our teleport wand.
Yes, everything is electrified.
I guess I can put some light on this.
Why not?
And why not just do something like this?
I mean, why not?
I mean, it's shuffle, but...
That's not bad.
That's actually...
That's a decent amount of damage, I would say.
And you know what?
Ah, but it's shuffle.
Hold on.
If I now do this...
What's that gonna do?
Okay, it shoots it off in random directions.
That's bad.
So what if we put both of those inside of that one?
No, that's bad as well.
Ah, the shuffle is fucking it up.
Yep, yep, yep.
It's bad.
It's a bit of a mess.
But it's what we got.
It's what we got.
Now.
I'm immune to electricity.
I have homing.
I have fungal disease.
I wonder if it's enough to kill Stuart.
Oh, plasma cutter.
I could make a little hole.
Hidey hide.
Eh, no, no, no, no.
I don't think I can kill him.
At least not count.
I do have the tablet.
Yo, what if I lead him into water and I...
Electrify him.
Yo.
Did we make a water trap?
I'm gonna...
Water everything.
This guy is about to have...
to get woken up.
You know what, worst case, we can teleport.
Worst case, I teleport out of here.
Yeah, and then we figure out a way to kill him.
But the thing is, he floats in the air, so I'm not actually going to be able to electrify him very, uh...
very well here.
What is this one?
Acceleration.
That would be nice to put on, actually.
So here's my plan.
He's gonna come here.
I'm gonna do this.
I just need to practice that throw.
Okay, that's the one.
That's the one.
So I start...
You know what?
With acceleration, maybe I can do it really crazy here.
Oh, it doesn't even gain the...
acceleration there when I throw it, really?
Oh, what?
What a scam!
Physics not being, uh, obeyed here.
Okay, well...
Let me try it even more.
If I jump from here and I aim here...
Wait, that's not...
No, I need to make this consistent.
There.
Okay, a little higher.
So when my cursor gets to here, and I stand here...
That could work.
A little higher.
That's the one.
That's consistent.
Maybe even better if I stand, like, on this wand.
Okay, I can throw it a little higher.
If this works, it's actually insane.
Oh, that's it.
I got it.
Okay, let's make him mad.
Uh, make him mad here.
Oh, here he comes.
Oh, come
on, come on.
Stuart, come here.
This needs to be timed perfectly.
No!
I hit him!
He didn't die from it.
We're gonna grab the tablet again.
Go!
Come here.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, no.
Okay, wait for him here.
Wait for him here.
Oh, it's so over.
Oh, fuck.
He's gotta be dead soon.
If I miss now, I leave.
We leave.
Go!
Okay.
Uh, no.
Ooh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Drink acceleration, let's go.
We are leaving.
Oh, yeah, electrify the shit out of this water.
Dude, this is actually a sick perk.
Stuart, are you coming towards me?
Is that what's happening?
Can I get down there?
I can't.
Um, what's the best way to do it?
That works.
Okay, so tablet strategy is terrible.
Don't ever try that again.
Yes, sure.
Let's take it.
Oh, nice.
Oh, my God.
Oh, this is getting a little dangerous.
What's that?
What is that?
Oh, wax.
Looked like a bone to me.
Also, we're low on HP.
It may be time to GTFO already.
It feels bad to say, but...
Okay, so here's the plan.
I'm going to pheromone him.
There we go.
You're not pheromoned.
Asshole.
I need that one.
I mean, this run is kind of ripped.
Fucking Stuart.
He's going to be haunting us till the end of days.
Now, that is something I like.
I'll take it.
I'm burning.
Oh, my three HP.
It's time to leave.
Oh, we got to go straight down, straight down, straight down.
I cannot take damage from this laser cutter now.
It just cannot happen.
So, what are we going to do?
I'm going to be standing.
Oh, this fire is though.
Okay, the fire's gone.
At an angle.
At an angle!
What the fuck was that?
Sorry, I need to understand what just happened.
That was bullshit.
Look, I was aiming down to the bottom right.
But somehow the fucking spell went down left?
What just happened?
That's bullshit.
I feel like I was cheated.
I did that so safely.
Huh.
That's weird.
All right, fair enough.
I guess I'll never do that while the water is electrified again.
Maybe that messed up the whole...
I don't know.
The vibe of the laser cutter or something.
Hmm.
All right, back in the hemisphere.
Okay, all I need is tinker with wands everywhere and peace with gods.
I know it's a lot.
But if I have those, I'm good.
I hate Stuart with a passion.
It's just...
I mean, I could have just gone on and not aggroed him, I guess.
Yeah.
I did the mistake.
I mean, I tested at least...
I tested the tablet method.
Didn't quite work out.
So now we know that for the future.
Like he has a lot of HP.
I think the only way to make it work with a tablet is if you can somehow give it enough momentum.
Maybe if I kick it.
I put the...
Dude, I put the tablet down and I kick the tablet.
That's way more momentum, right?
Maybe we gotta try to play football with that guy next time.
I don't know any football terminology here, but you know when they put the football up upright and someone comes running and kicks it?
That's me.
Yeah, I want to get up there.
No!
Don't scam me now.
Oh God, it's one of those shitty ones that has shitty recharge.
That's actually...
That's a nice one.
The magic arrow.
10 damage.
That's really good.
That is really good.
Also, I gotta stop soon because there is an event in the official Minecraft server on the Discord tonight.
And I don't want to stream at the same time.
Forgot exactly when that was.
Hold on, I need to check that.
Let's see here.
11.30.
Okay, yeah.
I also gotta get some food at some point.
That's fine.
I have some time.
Dude, the magic arrow is legit in this place.
Okay, so look at this.
Okay, this is not a clear symbol, I don't think.
Not that I can see.
Wait, maybe this?
Which one could it be?
Nope, I don't see it here.
But it could be a symbol I haven't translated yet.
Of course, it's possible.
Yo, that's a sick wand!
Look at that!
I mean, it's only two slots.
But this is a solid one.
Holy crap.
Damn.
Not bad at all.
I'm tempted.
I don't know.
I think this one may still be better.
But they're close.
Oh, there's more than one.
They were stacked.
Those fuckers.
They got me good.
That's fair.
Hamis' fight in packs.
Everyone knows that.
Boink.
Down you go.
Love it.
I'm being way too risky.
Also, I have polymorphine on me.
I...
Good thing I just noticed that.
Because I would be pouring that on myself.
No question if I was on fire.
Well, I guess it does clear fire.
I have unstable and...
Polymorphine, right?
What if I mix them?
Whoa, we're about to do some crazy experiments here.
Doesn't do anything.
We gotta add more stuff to that mix.
We're not done with that mix.
What if you add every liquid in the game together?
I wonder what happens then.
Okay, look at all these Hamises.
That's a clear tablet situation.
Also, is this the tablet I was translating before?
No, it wasn't.
No, it is, it is, it is.
Never mind.
I could go grab the tablet at the top.
But it's a little difficult with these fire bolts.
No!
Oh, wait, why did that release so much gold?
That works.
Look at all that water.
That's a good sign for me to pick it up.
Let's dispose of this.
Oh, hold on.
Oh, yeah.
Asshole.
I hate when they shoot you from off-screen, sort of.
Well, borderline off-screen.
Okay, so there's blood here.
Watch.
We're gonna try and pour this in.
And that into the blood.
Nothing.
All right.
Well, we tried.
Let's try and pour some shit into toxic sludge here.
There's also a chest that I really want to...
Oh, no, I'm on fire.
That's actually a problem.
Get into the blood, get into the blood.
There we go.
Grab the chest.
Okay, here we go.
Does that do anything?
No.
Mix, mix, mix.
Nothing happens.
What if we add a bit of blood to that mixture?
Wait, water?
There must have been a little water in here.
That's my only explanation.
Yeah, there must have been some water in there.
So, let's empty the polymorphine.
Not the most responsible place to do it.
I will admit that.
But it's gotta be done.
Let me grab some water from down here.
Just play it safe.
Damn it.
What?
Oh, I see.
I'm really going out of my way to kill you when you hit me.
That was not worth it at all.
Fuck.
There we go.
That is what I'm talking about.
Wait.
There's a wand?
Huh.
Five slots on it.
That's a decent wand.
I think I'll take it.
Thank you very much.
More water.
The Serkium.
Let's try and mix that with a bunch of things.
That was close.
There we go.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I'm dodging bullets here.
Oh, how am I not getting damaged?
That is so lucky.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
There we go.
Acceleration, you know.
So there's oil here.
It's a prime place to test.
Let's try and pour in some of this.
And that.
Mix it.
Nothing.
Okay.
So now we try...
Fucking get out of here.
Pour some of this in here as well.
Mix it.
Nothing.
All right.
Oh, that was beautiful.
10 out of 10.
That's worm pheromone.
We could try to mix things in here.
Water.
Some of this.
Uh-oh, be careful.
And that.
Makes it, makes it, makes it good.
Nothing.
Oh, they're gonna die from that.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, what the hell is happening?
Did that guy have a damage?
AOE or something?
Okay, we're leaving.
That was close.
Oh, man.
All right.
Yikes.
What the fuck is blood money?
That better be the most amazing thing.
Like, it better be like 20,000 gold every time you kill an enemy.
I don't see how this can be worth it otherwise.
Okay, so I'm gonna try new things, right?
That's what I said.
Let's try new things.
We're trying to try the boomerang.
Who knows?
Maybe it's incredible.
I wonder how much extra damage.
We can test it.
So this does 10 damage.
25!
Okay, that's...
That's not bad.
That's not bad at all.
Holy crap.
So how does...
Let me put this one.
This is five damage.
What?
Percentage wise, that's way more damage.
This went from 10 to 25.
Which is a little over 100 percent.
This is like 400 percent.
The hell?
That's really good on that.
Look at the damage here.
Wait, it does come back to me.
You know, that could be really good with something that can go through enemies multiple times.
If I find unlimited spells, it could be nice with a rock.
Well, everything's nice with a rock.
I want this.
Replace that.
Give me that one.
Oh, all of these are actually great.
I love the sparkle with trigger.
It's one of my favorites.
How about the ones themselves?
Are they any good?
0.22, 0.08.
I guess this one is decent, but I have pretty good ones already.
So, for example, this one.
This is actually, this is going to be a lot of damage, I think.
Holy shit!
Okay, I'm happy I tried new things.
That is incredible.
I don't even mind that they come back.
As long as they don't hurt me, of course.
And you know what else?
If we find healing bolt, well, there it is.
That's an automatic healing.
That works straight out of the box.
But even better.
We run out of mana quick with that.
Hold up now.
Let's try something wild here.
Probably not going to have enough mana for this.
183, baby!
Oh, yeah!
Let's put this in here.
Oh, that's not bad.
That's a lot of damage!
If only we can reduce the recharge rate a bit.
Then we're golden.
Can I double dip that one?
Doesn't look like it, unfortunately.
No.
Oh, can we?
All right, fine.
Whatever.
So that's cool.
Maybe we put it on this one instead.
Has a higher charge.
Let me see.
That's 10, 5, 5...
Oh, we can totally do this.
That's totally going to work.
Oh!
Guys, this is insane!
The boomerang!
Holy fuck!
Can we go another round?
Is that working the way I think?
Yes, it is.
Look at that.
Hold on.
Yeah.
So what's happening here?
We're shooting one spark bolt with trigger.
When it impacts, it shoots triple scatter spell with these three inside.
And then it shoots the light.
And what is it modifying?
That one.
But what does that do?
Triggers these!
So we actually get two shots of this wand for the price of one, so to speak, before the recharge kicks in.
You see that?
Recharge.
But if I take it away.
Constant recharge.
You see that?
I put it here.
What if I do this?
That should work the same way.
It's the exact...
Oh, is that even better then?
Because I fire another one.
1100?
Wait, what?
I must have crit there or something.
Yo, this is nuts.
So we have so much men on this, we could maybe even afford to do this.
Oh, it's close.
It's close.
Yep, look at that.
Oh, wow!
Oh, you're seeing the damage.
Holy fuck.
And then when we put Berserkium on, my...
This is the best one I've ever had in this stage in the game, I think.
I took this perk thinking, oh, it's gonna be shit.
But let's just do it to get it on the progress card or whatever.
But I am so happy I did.
This is game changing.
I'll take some rocks as well while we're at it.
That could be cool.
And that one.
Uh, yeah, sure.
Hold on.
Oh, I don't have enough money.
Right, okay.
And the cool thing about this is I have three empty ones now, so I have lots of room to find new things.
This is shuffled, so it's bad.
I'm just gonna replace it immediately, I think.
With that one.
All right, let's go.
And yeah, we're not gonna bother with Stuart.
Not this time, baby.
Oh my goodness.
Holy shit.
Oh man, we're gonna be unstoppable.
Is that a wand?
Thanks!
Huh?
All right, well, that's my digging wand.
That's incredible.
Unfortunately, I cannot really dig unless I...
Oh,
wait, the boomerang!
The boomerang!
Oh, it makes sense.
Fuck, I thought I was about to die.
God damn it.
Okay, yeah, you know what?
That's not happening then.
Nope.
God damn it, man.
As soon as I fucking get something good going, that happens.
But you know what?
I guess I learned the lesson just now.
Yeah.
So, actually, I learned a big lesson.
When I have this, don't take any spells that can damage you.
None.
Sip, nada.
You will die.
Because it's basically homing, but on yourself.
That means no glowing lance.
Oh, wait, glowing lance?
Does that actually do self-damage?
I'm not so sure.
I'm not going to test it.
I honestly don't remember.
I don't think it does.
That was scary.
I thought for sure I died there.
I thought that was the end.
Why did I just take damage?
Out from these guys?
It is kind of annoying that the spells come back to me.
Like, they don't fly as far.
So I need to put speed on them.
That's the trick here.
I mean, sure, I'll take it.
Wow.
Here's the thing.
I don't mind moving on already because I already do so much damage.
I'm not worried about my damage situation.
So we're going to go down to the portal.
While we can.
Blood, that's fine with me.
Let's go.
Man.
Close encounter with death there.
No money though.
So that's a bummer.
Good thing there's nothing of value anyway.
Stainless armor.
No, we're going to try new perks.
Let's try this.
Rage-fueled levitation.
I am trying new things today.
Let's see how good that is.
Oh yeah, it did restore some.
Wow, I do good damage here.
This is good damage.
Hold on, is that even a...
That may actually be a good thing.
I'm going to do a little bit of digging with that.
There's not a lot, but it'll work in a pinch.
What's going on in here, guys?
Egg.
Uh, no.
No.
Don't want egg.
Bam.
What a kick.
Can I even get in there?
Wow, that sucks.
Actually, I need to only get here.
Hey, a double.
Not bad.
I shall acquire it.
What was this?
Oh, is that the one that I just dropped, I think.
It's a wand?
Um, yeah.
I'll take that.
Seems cool.
I like the boomerang, guys.
This, I mean, it comes with some drawbacks, of course.
Also, oh man, if I'm going to do black holes later, that shit's going to come back to me.
That's not going to be super effective.
At least, not for the purposes I have in mind with it.
Formation Pentagon.
You know, that is not a bad spell.
Trigger into Formation Pentagon?
Five of these bubble sparks.
Chew on that for a moment.
How does that taste in your mouth?
I think it tastes wonderful.
Whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop.
Kill him.
Blow it up.
Get rid of all the hazards.
Holy shit!
That was a lot of gold!
Where did that guy go?
Glass.
I've never seen this.
Look at that damage I do.
It's actually wild.
One thing is for sure, you don't want to use bloodlust now.
Oh, that is the last spell you want to use.
At least with this wand.
Ah, wow, wow, wow, wow.
One shot it.
Can I dig through there?
I have this one.
No, wait, it's Pentagon.
It's going to shoot it everywhere.
That's bad.
I am actually in need of some digging.
I cannot dig anywhere.
Oh my god, that's Ambrosia.
We can get it.
Empty this.
All the way.
You know what, let's try and make some things in Ambrosia.
Water.
That one.
Makes it.
What about some blood?
No?
Okay.
Worth a try.
Oh wait, I hear a uku.
I think.
No, it's just the heads.
Oh, no, no.
Oh man, they took a lot of HP from me there.
Thieves, stealing my HP.
There we go.
Taking care of.
Yeah, I need digging.
I mean, I have a great setup right now.
I just need some...
extra utility spells here.
Teleport would be nice.
But I would much prefer digging.
You know, there's another downside to this boomerang.
Is that it's hard to tell which spells sometimes are mine and which ones are the enemy.
So I sometimes try to dodge my own spells.
I should have put some light on this instead.
I now regret my actions.
Yeah, look at that.
I thought someone shot at me.
It's hard to tell what's mine.
I just want to go to the inverted pyramid right now.
And then I want to grab the health here.
Oh.
Concentrated light.
I think I want it.
That's a spell I kind of want to make a wand out of at some point, because it seems really cool.
I love the effect of it when you shoot it.
It's very pleasing to the eye and the ears.
Sometimes that's all that matters.
Going pretty well.
Shoots the heart.
That's the pheromone shot.
Or is it?
I'm not sure.
Here it is.
The orb room.
Interesting that it's just called the orb room.
Oh, here we go.
All right, let me take some pictures.
Second picture.
Here.
Okay, I got it.
Let's find the letters we need now.
What are we missing?
A, B, C, D, E.
We need a capital E.
Do we have it?
We do.
It's basically like an O again, but more like a triangular or a diamond D shape.
You know what?
Let me make this tiny bit smaller.
That way we have some room here.
A, B, C, D, E.
So E is like this.
There we go.
Do we have a C?
Emerald tablet volume B.
Volume five.
Okay, so no capital C unless it appears in the text.
I'm just realizing maybe there's some kind of cipher hidden in this.
Interestingly, they also catalyze a lot of letters in the text.
There's got to be a capital C somewhere.
There's count.
Once.
What else are we needing?
A, B, C, D, E, F.
Do we have an F?
We do first.
Oh, but there's like a little apostrophe as well.
Even that is like translated.
So big F is like a weird K with a missing line.
So we got to write like this.
Let's see here.
Like that.
That's a K.
No, that's an F.
Capital H.
Do we have that?
Capital H maybe.
We do holy hand grenade.
One, two, three, four.
It's an R.
With a colon.
All E, holy hand.
Oh yeah, it is.
R with a colon.
Very cool.
There we go.
That's the H.
J.
Show me the J.
J is elusive, man.
Where is the number J?
J.
Lobest thou thy holy hand grenade of Antioch towards thy foe, who being naughty in my sight shall snuff it.
There's no J.
All right, that's fine.
How about an O?
Oh yeah, we have that.
Volume.
It's sort of the same as the O.
That is not capitalized.
But a little different.
Let me do this in two rows here.
Like that.
So O is like this weird L.
Big O.
What about K?
Do we have a K?
There's no K.
At least not a not a capital K.
Damn it.
Okay.
P maybe.
Not that I...
Oh, holy pin.
We got a P. It's a weird X again.
Was P also an X over here?
It was, but it's a different X this time.
Not that it matters.
I mean, does it matter if it's capitalized or not?
It's very similar.
Like look at this.
The arrow here is very similar to the S here.
It's not quite an arrow, but it's like...
Some of them are different.
Some of them are not, basically.
So this one is more like this.
And then it has a little like that.
That's a P. T-U-V is the question mark.
There we go.
Very cool.
H-F.
All that we got.
What about big N?
Oh, we have that already.
Cool.
Big M.
We have that one too.
Big L.
Rest in peace.
Okay, I think we're slowly getting there.
Now let's see the non-capital letters.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J.
There's got to be a small J here somewhere.
I refuse to believe it, but there's not.
There's not.
Wow, okay.
K then.
There's got to be a K.
There is.
First, shalt thou take...
one, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
It's an R.
What?
Whoa, hold on.
That's got to be a mistake.
One, two, three, four.
And it's the third.
Oh yeah.
Oh, it's just the R without the colon.
Interesting.
That comes before L.
Oh no, wait.
Non-capitalized.
Hold on.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, O, E, L, C.
K.
It's just the R.
I like the weird looking R.
Okay.
Nice.
L, M, N, O, P, Q.
There's no Q here, I don't think.
That's kind of a rare letter.
Unless quest is mentioned.
Or quite.
Antioch.
Hold on, we have a C already.
Towards life bow.
Okay.
We got that.
X, Y.
Do we have a Y?
That's quite a norm.
We do.
Lobbest thou thy.
Okay.
So that's like a weird thingy.
Looks like this.
Lobbest thou.
Nope.
I fucked it up.
Like that.
Is that right?
Lobbest thou thy.
No, it's kind of wrong.
It's like this.
That's why.
We got it.
But wait, where's the A?
And O.
Nah, kidding.
That's the Danish language.
We don't do that here.
Let's see if we can find some comma and shit.
So comma is...
Yeah, comma is quite confirmed there.
So a dot punctuation mark.
That's three dots.
One dot.
Cool.
All right, we got commas.
What about a dash?
A dash is a little arrow.
Cool.
That's really neat.
We're going to put a title for this, by the way.
This has to be called...
Oh man, of course.
It's got to be called a reset of stone, given that we're taking the stones and using this.
It's got to be...
a reset of stone.
What a beautiful stone it is.
Make it a bit bigger.
There we go.
Awesome.
But that's it, because now we're going to keep going.
More translation has been done.
I'm sure I missed a couple letters there, but let's find another tablet and continue on.
What's up, fool?
Whoever you are, you're dead.
Now I kind of want to find the book in...
What's that place called?
The fungal caverns.
If I remember correctly, that also is being translated live when you mouse over it.
Wait, how am I going to get in there?
I think over here is okay.
I mean, we also have the tablet on top of the mountain.
We can go check out, of course.
I can't wait to get to all the...
the pyramid and all the other places where we know there's text.
Dude, even the start of the game.
The stone monuments there have text on them as well.
Oh, it's got to be so much fun.
We're finally going to get to the bottom of this.
What is that?
It's wax.
Okay.
As in a candle or what?
Wait, what's that?
That's a wand.
I'm just clearing for enemies here.
Oh, he died.
What's that?
That's bone.
Can I eat bone?
Is there really no good way in?
That is almost unbelievable.
I may have to use this wand just for this purpose.
That does cut, right?
Oh wait, does this damage me?
Oh, it doesn't.
Okay, thank God.
It does not dig, unfortunately.
Does this dig?
It does not.
I know this one does.
But you got to sort of...
You know what?
I can do that.
No, wait, wait.
It's Pentagon.
That's bad.
This is better.
If anything...
What?
Bro, I can't get in here.
It's locked off to me.
That's actually wild.
Guess I'll not go in.
Come on.
Oh wait, there's a little hole.
Yes!
The little hole.
Oh, but there's no way for me to get in here, though.
Yeah, rip.
Never mind.
I have no digging.
Leave me alone!
Stuck!
There we go.
All right.
It's time to leave.
I'm stuck here again.
We got to go all the way around.
This is a very annoying magical temple.
Holy crap.
The layout here is pissing me off.
But it's only frustrating because I don't have any digging.
Oh, what do we have here?
Something I can't get to.
Unless...
It does dig.
But it's horrendous.
But maybe it's just enough.
Oh no.
Oh wait, that's not too bad.
The digging.
It's sort of real.
Huh.
500 meta charge speed.
I like it more than that.
But this is actually a really good one.
Three slots, though.
Maybe I will replace this one.
Yup.
Come on.
Go, go, go.
Don't die, don't die.
Here we go.
Let me out of here.
Also, I can dig now with this.
91.
HP, that's not bad.
We can explore a bit more.
Ouch.
Come on, water me!
Why is it not working?
That was disastrous.
Wow!
What?
I thought I was plenty HP.
I don't know.
I need to see that replay.
I guess the fire killed me.
I took way too much damage from that.
The fire.
Wait, how much damage did that final one do?
That final shot did a sick amount of damage to me.
Let me see.
Can I tell?
33.
Yikes.
Ouch.
Was that from a fireball?
I think it was.
Let's see it.
There it comes.
Bump!
33 damage.
Yikes.
So the fire into...
I was trying to water myself for like a solid five seconds.
Nothing happened.
I don't understand why.
I must have missed myself.
I was floating while trying to do it.
Dammit.
98 deaths.
Almost at 100.
Okay, but I'm gonna stop here.
Because I need to go get some food before the stores close.
And there's the official Minecraft server anniversary event tonight.
Check it out on the Discord.
Man, I didn't get far tonight, huh?
Actually, that's not true.
Gameplay-wise, I didn't get very far.
I died a lot.
I made stupid mistakes.
But the whole translation thing made up for it.
I loved sitting and doing that.
You know what?
I think that was the trade-off this time.
I had so much fun with that.
Dark Anvil.
Hello, Mr. Translator.
It's me!
What's up?
How you doing?
Translation and boomerang discovery.
Yeah, I can't believe I've been sleeping on the boomerang.
But let's be honest.
From the description, it doesn't sound too great, does it?
But that's the thing about these perks.
You gotta try them before you judge them.
I think I also thought vampirism was shit for a while.
Until I tried it and then it was like...
For a while, it was my number one perk in the game.
Now, not so much more.
You need to borrow the Nomai translation device.
Oh yeah, exactly.
You know, I was about to call a reference there to that game.
But I didn't do it.
Just because I didn't want to say anything, you know?
Plasma Boomerang was fun too.
Yeah, that one and then...
Oh, you know what?
Actually, remember the first plasma I died to?
I must have had a similar thing happen there.
That actually explains it.
I must have had a spell like a homing or...
Oh no, it wasn't homing.
It was the spell where it goes where your cursor is.
The aiming arc or whatever.
That's gotta be it.
In like 200 hours of gameplay, I never realized the translation stuff.
Dude, I'm almost at 200 hours as well.
And I just realized it.
Well, okay, not quite.
I'm at 130 hours.
But like the whole...
When you mouse over a tablet, the way it like changes immediately, I never thought about that until today.
Because I've been looking for like a cipher or a key or a reset of stone in this game.
Similar to a certain other game.
I don't want to spoil too much from that game.
But you know, you know what I mean?
Like if you can start small and build up a library of translation or like symbols, you can slowly get there, right?
I'm kind of sad I didn't discover this earlier.
I don't know.
I noticed that as soon as I grabbed the tablet for the first time.
Was translating things early.
It makes sense.
I mean, I guess it's one of those things that where if you notice it immediately, it's obvious.
But if if you assume like I did, oh, it's just a neat little animation to tell you that, oh, this is some alien language, but here is translated for you.
You know, I didn't think much of it.
And then in my mind, I never even considered any other options because I automatically accepted that thing as being the way they did it.
You know what I mean?
You looked for a reset of stone, but it was an entire reset of brick house all along.
You don't want to throw a reset of stones around when you live in a reset of brick house.
It is a cool effect.
I even commented on that.
I think the first time I thought, oh, that's a nice effect.
And that's it.
Then out of my brain, you know, I didn't consider that ever again.
You know, if I was a developer, I would put a message somewhere in the game, just saying, congrats, you translated this and nothing more like some text somewhere.
Very important place, you know, on top of a statue flanked by giants.
Mountains or whatever make it super important.
And then when you finally translate it, it's just some bullshit.
I hope I get to find something like that.
Oliver, if mountains were made of silver and gold, what would they profit a man who lives in a constant fear of death?
Not much.
I mean, what are you going to use your money on if you're dead, right?
Maybe that's the message.
I
think Tabula Smarragdina is a real stone from real life.
Did you know that Heezy in Finnish almost translates to demon?
I didn't know that.
But that's so easy.
The message is the massage message is 72 damage from tablet hit.
Isn't Heezy goblin?
That sounds more right to me.
They kind of look like goblins, actually.
You know, the green skin, all that.
Makes sense to me.
Do you expect to play much more of this game?
I love the series.
I definitely.
I'm not done yet.
But like I said before, I may start playing something else soon, but I will occasionally return to this.
Just because of the noita itch, it's real for me.
Like I'm starting to dream about this game.
I had a dream the other night.
About finding the perfect combination of spells that made the most OP wand ever.
And then promptly forgetting what the combination was.
And I couldn't find it again.
I couldn't get back to that combination.
It was it was a nightmare.
It could be goblin and devil at the same time or demon.
It could be whatever we wanted to be.
Become a vampire in real life.
I think I already am.
I barely go outside.
I live like a hermit.
You know, when I go outside, I look up, I go.
Because the sun is shining.
Understanding the wand mechanics changed my real life thinking capabilities.
You go out to your bicycle and you're like, huh, if I sit this way with this thing in my hand and my foot on the right pedal at this angle, then it's more optimal to cycle in a straight line compared to a non-straight line.
What's the best game you've ever played?
Oh, that's easy.
World of Warcraft classic.
Hands down.
But that's multiplayer.
I think my favorite single player of all time.
I'm not sure yet, but I think it's Outer Wilds.
Because, OK, so I would have said not Outer Wilds maybe a couple of weeks ago, but then I started watching a let's play of it from Pirate Software.
I've seen other let's plays of it, too, but it's just that whenever I watch a let's play of it again, I'm reminded how fucking good that game was.
You know, just hearing the music again puts me right back into that mood.
Damn, what a game.
More like spells or like words and conscious, active thinking can make magic happen.
So like quantum mechanics.
Words behave differently when you observe them.
What do you think of Life is Strange?
I played the first Life is Strange.
I fucking loved it.
I really loved it.
Incredible game.
I cried like a bitch during that.
There are certain times in that game, man.
Wow.
The Waterworks just were on 24-7.
Thinking of buying an indie game for the weekend.
I guess Outer Wilds it is.
I don't know if that is considered an indie game.
Maybe it is.
It's definitely a small studio, I think.
But yeah, man, go for it.
It's a lot of fun.
Being 100% genuine, I've watched a lot of supercuts of Outer Wilds playthroughs.
And yours is with no question the best one.
Aw, man, thanks, dude.
Your deep interest in theories and also just random chance stuff that perfectly worked.
I thought for the longest time people didn't enjoy my slow style because I am playing very slow in that game.
I would waste whole...
Okay, I'm not going to talk more because I don't want to spoil it for anyone listening.
But I was going slow, okay?
Which was a detriment to me at times.
But I had a blast.
It was so much fun to figure out.
Is Edith Finch on your game list?
I'm not sure it is.
I have heard about it.
I can check it.
Hold on.
Backlocked.
Maybe it is.
You mean what remains of Edith Finch, right?
It is on my backlog.
In fact, here it is if you want to check out what is on there and what is not on there.
Ma was one.
Hey, man.
Good to see you.
Missed the stream.
First time chatting here.
Nice to hang out with you.
Found you through a supercut of your playthrough of Outer Wilds.
And then kept watching.
Enjoy your noise of playthrough.
Man, a lot of people found me through that supercut of Elis.
That video went kind of viral.
It's crazy.
I think it's because of the title of it.
He titled it...
Astrophysicist Explores the Outer Wilds or something.
And then after that, I changed the title of the first video of my playlist to Astrophysicist Plays as well.
And it worked.
It worked.
Those clickbait titles.
Well, it's not really clickbait, I guess, in this case.
But it just feels like it is a little bit.
It's always fun when you figure out something really complex just to miss something very simple.
Dude, that's my life.
I shit you not.
I overthink everything.
And miss the simple things.
It's the story of my life.
Yo, there's a new Life is Strange coming.
29th of October.
Really?
But wait, isn't there already a strange...
I was about to say, strange new life.
Life is Strange 2?
Isn't that already out?
With Max Caulfield.
Oh, lovely.
I'm most likely going to check that out.
Oh, gee, gangster demon plays applied.
I was thinking of making something like that as a joke once.
Just a really over-the-top video, you know, with an over-the-top thumbnail and just leaning into the whole thing.
Just for fun.
It's descriptive, which can help pique your interest.
Knowing an actual astrophysicist plays a game about space is interesting because they'll have information tidbits to share.
I feel like I didn't share that much from that perspective.
And maybe this is a weird stance to have, but like...
So I've been studying this stuff for like, pretty much half of my life at this point.
And in the beginning, it was like a big passion of mine, you know?
I would talk about astro-related things to everyone I could, you know?
But then I've been doing it so long now that it's become so much of a job.
Then at the end of the day, I just don't want to talk about it anymore, even though I love it a lot.
You know, like, I don't want to spill too much of it.
Like, I just want to leave work at work, you know what I mean?
It's not like that all the time, but for a while it was like that for me.
And I kind of hated that because I used to be so passionate about it.
I still am to an extent, but nowhere near the level when I first started.
I would say games are definitely a bigger passion of mine.
It's something that has never subsided for me.
My parents used to tell me...
Like, I played so many video games as a child, especially when World of Warcraft Classic was out, man.
I was sometimes skipping school to play that shit.
Like, I was loving it.
And they would think something's wrong with me.
I remembered my mom took me to a psychiatrist once.
He plays too many video games.
What is wrong with him?
And we had a whole talk.
And at the end, the psychiatrist was like, nah, that's pretty normal.
He's a young guy.
He's a young kid.
They love video games.
I wouldn't think too much about it, you know?
And then she would tell me after that, well, one day you're going to grow out of it.
It's just a phase.
Later on, you're not going to play as many video games, you know?
She couldn't be more wrong.
I play more video games now than I've ever done.
I love it.
It's the best thing.
It's an escape from everything.
Not that I hate everything, but...
I just like it more, I guess.
It was in the face, mom.
Exactly.
I'm not sure if video gaming is hip nowadays to moms and dads.
And their children.
I don't know.
Maybe it is.
I feel like most would restrict the time on the computer, even today.
Do you ever get a dizzy...
Do you ever get dizzy watching the night sky?
I have a love-hate relationship with it because it feels too vast and it's overwhelming.
No, I think it's awesome.
I love...
I love looking at the night sky.
One of the best things is to lie down on the grass.
Like, almost like a snow angel position, you know, where you feel with your hands the grass and your feet are, like, stretched out.
And then you try to imagine that you're, like, holding on to the earth as it spins, you know?
So, you know how when something spins, centrifugal force, everything gets spun out?
You're trying to resist that, you know?
You hold on to the grass and you look up at the sky and you just try to feel the rotation of the earth.
When you look up at the sky, there's just something magical about it.
That's one of the coolest things ever.
You should try it.
There's something comforting for me, looking at the night sky.
Knowing that we're nothing, that whatever happens here on earth doesn't matter at all in the grand scheme of things.
At least to me, that's a very calming thing.
I know some people get anxiety from that, and that's totally legit as well.
Oh, God, when I do this, I feel truly insane.
Let me tell you what makes me insane, Sino Christ.
This is going to be so hard to describe, but...
if you... if you try to imagine not...
Okay, this is going to get a little ridiculous, maybe.
But if you try to imagine never being born, like, try to imagine not existing.
What did it feel like before you were here?
That feeling scares me so much.
This feeling of not being here.
You know what I mean?
Just right now, I get this existential, like, almost black hole in my heart when I think about it.
It's like I can feel it.
Maybe I don't communicate it very well right now, but just trying to imagine nothingness for me, that's the crazy thing.
The not having a consciousness or existing.
Man, that fucks me up.
I like how this chat went all existential and philosophical.
With COVID-19, gaming became more popular.
Yeah!
That's awesome.
More people need to be enlightened by the beauty that is gaming.
I play games with my kids.
I found a big community of parents that, dude, that's awesome, Raven Warrior.
I would have loved if my parents played video games with me as a child.
They did very rarely, but that sounds super sick, man.
That's cool.
Hop on the existential crisis train.
What the hell?
Reminds me of trying to imagine how it would be to be blind.
Because it's not black, it's just nothing.
Apparently, if you try seeing out of your needs like the same thing...
Wait, what?
I'm trying to imagine it now.
I instinctively closed my eyes.
I can't imagine that.
Another thing that really blows me out of the water is trying to imagine more than three dimensions.
You know how flat land?
You imagine that everything is in two dimensions, right?
And when a three-dimensional being comes into contact with it, like, say, a sphere, it starts off as this point, right, that spreads out to become a circle with a maximum radius, and then it decreases again until it becomes a point again.
Try to imagine some four-dimensional thing moving through our dimension.
That breaks my brain.
And that's honestly a little scary.
Trying to imagine multiple dimensions or, like, more than three dimensions.
Because
you can't see anything out of your knee, right?
That's how it is for blind people, just in the eyes.
I see what you mean.
Like, when you close your eyes, you are seeing something, right?
You're seeing darkness.
Whereas if you're really blind, you don't even get that sensation.
Or maybe you do, I don't know.
I've never been blind.
Well, I'm blind quite often, but in a different way.
You can almost imagine the fourth dimension, but just as I see it, it's gone.
You know what's funny?
There is a very old, but very renowned, lecturer at the University of Copenhagen who would teach quantum mechanics and string theory and all that stuff.
His name was Holger Pick.
And he was a really funny old man, you know?
He would wear this bicycle helmet everywhere he went.
And he had this funny voice.
He would be like, Yes!
And then in four dimensions, he would talk like that, right?
And at some point during his lectures, he is so deep in thought.
He would just say random shit like, Okay, so imagine you're in, like, imagine 40 dimensions.
Just imagine that right now.
And you could see in his mind, he was imagining it.
You know, that guy was on another level.
And we're just sitting there like, I'm sorry, we can't imagine that.
But okay, keep going.
Good times, man.
He's not teaching anymore.
So he retired some time ago, but he still hangs around the university quite often.
Because it's his life, you know?
He still gives talks.
He still talks to students, but he doesn't get paid.
He's just there.
It's freaking awesome.
You love thinking about four dimensional geometry.
Oh, man, it is exciting.
I love watching YouTube videos that delve into those topics.
Because no matter what, you can't really show four dimensions, no matter how hard you try, right?
Because we're limited here in this three dimensional world.
Man, this is getting too crazy.
What is this even noise anymore?
Okay, so I have like 20 minutes, 25 minutes until the store closes.
I will have to go get some sustenance, because I have a date with someone else to watch some Starcraft tournament tonight.
The biggest Starcraft two tournament that has ever been is happening right now.
And I'm freaking excited about it.
I need to watch it.
So thank you, everybody, for joining.
It's been an absolute pleasure again.
And I'll see you next time.
And thanks for subscribing to those that did and following.
I really appreciate it.
If you haven't checked it out yet, check out the YouTube channel.
I will rate another streamer right now.
So stay around.